[
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which year marks fall of Constantinople",
        "answer": 1453,
        "choices": [
            1453,
            1454,
            1452,
            1455
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who discovered America",
        "answer": "Christopher Columbus",
        "choices": [
            "Christopher Columbus",
            "Vasco Da Gama",
            "Prince Henry The Navigator",
            "Captain Hawkins"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Treaty of Tordesillias was signed between",
        "answer": "Spain & Portugal",
        "choices": [
            "Spain & Portugal",
            "Spain & England",
            "Portugal & England",
            "Greece & Spain"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who discovered all sea route from Europe to India",
        "answer": "Vasco Da Gama",
        "choices": [
            "Vasco Da Gama",
            "Christopher Columbus",
            "Captain Hawkins",
            "Afonso de Albuquerque"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In which year was the first regulating act passed to regulate the administration of the East India Company in India",
        "answer": 1773,
        "choices": [
            1773,
            1774,
            1775,
            1772
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In which year Pitt's India Act enacted",
        "answer": 1784,
        "choices": [
            1784,
            1783,
            1786,
            1785
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who introduced Permanent Settlement system of revenue collection",
        "answer": "Charles Cornwallis",
        "choices": [
            "Charles Cornwallis",
            "Warren Hastings",
            "Robert Clive",
            "William Pitt"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who introduced the system of Subsidiary Alliance",
        "answer": "Richard Wellesley",
        "choices": [
            "Richard Wellesley",
            "Charles Cornwallis",
            "Warren Hastings",
            "Robert Clive"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the leader of the Ghadar Movement, a revolutionary movement aimed at overthrowing British rule in India?",
        "answer": "Kartar Singh Sarabha",
        "choices": [
            "Kartar Singh Sarabha",
            "Lala Lajpat Rai",
            "Bhagat Singh",
            "Sardar Uddham Singh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The term Girmitiya refers to",
        "answer": "Indian indentured laborers sent to work overseas under contract",
        "choices": [
            "Indian indentured laborers sent to work overseas under contract",
            "British planters in India",
            "Indian traders in Southeast Asia",
            "Foreign slaves in India"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The word Girmitiya is derived from",
        "answer": "The English word agreement",
        "choices": [
            "The English word agreement",
            "The Hindi word grihapati",
            "A Sanskrit term meaning worker",
            "A Persian word meaning servant"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The system of indentured labor was introduced primarily after",
        "answer": "The abolition of slavery in the British Empire",
        "choices": [
            "The abolition of slavery in the British Empire",
            "The arrival of the British in India",
            "The end of the Mughal Empire",
            "The Industrial Revolution in Britain"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who laid the foundation of new landed aristocracy in Bengal?",
        "answer": "Murshid Quli Khan",
        "choices": [
            "Murshid Quli Khan",
            "Mir Jafar",
            "Mir Qasim",
            "Shah Alam"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the first Portugese Viceroy in India?",
        "answer": "Almeida",
        "choices": [
            "Almeida",
            "Diaz",
            "Vasco da Gama",
            "Albuquerque"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who used Hooghly as a base for piracy in the Bay of Bengal?",
        "answer": "Portugeese",
        "choices": [
            "Portugeese",
            "Dutch",
            "French",
            "British"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Dutch East India Company established its factory at Patna in which year?",
        "answer": 1632,
        "choices": [
            1632,
            1601,
            1774,
            1651
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Where in India did Britishers set up their first factory in 1613?",
        "answer": "Surat",
        "choices": [
            "Surat",
            "Goa",
            "Hooghly",
            "Amarkot"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which of the British officials defeated Portugeese at Sowlley?",
        "answer": "Thomas Best",
        "choices": [
            "Thomas Best",
            "William Hawkins",
            "Josiah Child",
            "Thomas Roe"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which one of the following was the immediate cause of First Carnatic War?",
        "answer": "Capture of French ships by British",
        "choices": [
            "Capture of French ships by British",
            "Anglo-French Rivalry",
            "Austrian War of Succession",
            "Issues of Carnatic Succession"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Identify the region from where Europeans got best shora (Saltpetre) and opium",
        "answer": "Bihar",
        "choices": [
            "Bihar",
            "Gujarat",
            "Bengal",
            "Madras"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "During British rule which region of India was famous for the production of opium?",
        "answer": "Bihar",
        "choices": [
            "Bihar",
            "Gujarat",
            "Assam",
            "Bengal"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Emperor Shah Alam II gave the Diwani of Bengal, Bihar and Orissa to East India Company on",
        "answer": "12th  August 1765",
        "choices": [
            "12th  August 1765",
            "18th  August 1765",
            "29th  August 1765",
            "21st  August 1765"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which treaty was signed after the Battle of Buxar?",
        "answer": "Treaty of Allahabad",
        "choices": [
            "Treaty of Allahabad",
            "Treaty of Sugauli",
            "Treaty of Bassein",
            "Treaty of Salbai"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the Commander-in-chief of the English forces during the Buxar war?",
        "answer": "Hector Munro",
        "choices": [
            "Hector Munro",
            "Campbell",
            "Holwell",
            "Neill"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was appointed Deputy Diwan of Murshidabad by Robert Clive after the Allahabad Treaty?",
        "answer": "Muhammad Raza Khan",
        "choices": [
            "Muhammad Raza Khan",
            "Shitab Rai",
            "Rai Durlabh",
            "Syed Ghulam Hussain"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The famous Battle of Wandiwash in 1760 was fought by the British against whom?",
        "answer": "French",
        "choices": [
            "French",
            "Dutch",
            "Mysore",
            "Portugese"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which city of Bihar was made capital in lieu of Murshidabad by Mir Qasim?",
        "answer": "Munger",
        "choices": [
            "Munger",
            "Rajgir",
            "Patna",
            "Darbhanga"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Robert Lytton is not associated with which of the following?",
        "answer": "Ilbert Bill",
        "choices": [
            "Ilbert Bill",
            "Strachey Commission",
            "Arms act",
            "Vernacular Press act"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Ranjeet Singh got famous Kohinoor diamond from",
        "answer": "Shah Shuja",
        "choices": [
            "Shah Shuja",
            "Zaman Shah",
            "Dost Mohammad",
            "Sher Ali"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Tipu Sultan set up his capital at",
        "answer": "Srirangapatnam",
        "choices": [
            "Srirangapatnam",
            "Mysore",
            "Bangalore",
            "Coimbatore"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Englishmen made the Treaty of Srirangapatnam with",
        "answer": "Tipu Sultan",
        "choices": [
            "Tipu Sultan",
            "Hyder Ali",
            "Dupleix",
            "Nandraj"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the first Governor General of India?",
        "answer": "William Bentinck",
        "choices": [
            "William Bentinck",
            "Warren Hastings",
            "Charles Canning",
            "Robert Lytton"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In which year, first Census was introduced in India?",
        "answer": 1872,
        "choices": [
            1872,
            1901,
            1911,
            1921
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who said, A single shelf of a good European library was worth the whole native literature of India and Arabia?",
        "answer": "Thomas Babington Macaulay",
        "choices": [
            "Thomas Babington Macaulay",
            "Dr William Carey",
            "Charles Grant",
            "John Elliot - Minto"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who among the following abolished Dual Government system in Bengal?",
        "answer": "Warren Hastings",
        "choices": [
            "Warren Hastings",
            "Robert Clive",
            "Charles Cornwallis",
            "Richard Wellesley"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The policy of Security Cell or Ring Fence policy is related to",
        "answer": "Warren Hastings",
        "choices": [
            "Warren Hastings",
            "James Andrew - Dalhousie",
            "Charles Cornwallis",
            "Robert Clive"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The dual system of governance in Bengal was enforced by",
        "answer": "Robert Clive",
        "choices": [
            "Robert Clive",
            "Warren Hastings",
            "William Bentinck",
            "George Curzon"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who is considered the Father of Diarchy?",
        "answer": "Lionel Curtis",
        "choices": [
            "Lionel Curtis",
            "Robert Clive",
            "Hector Munro",
            "Thomas Babington Macaulay"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "First Maratha Sardar to accept the subsidiary alliance of Richard Wellesley was",
        "answer": "Peshwa Bajirao II",
        "choices": [
            "Peshwa Bajirao II",
            "Raghuji Bhosle",
            "Daulat Rao Scindia",
            "Bhalaji Rao"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Under whose leadership was the suppresson of Thugs achieved?",
        "answer": "Captain William Henry Sleeman",
        "choices": [
            "Captain William Henry Sleeman",
            "Robert Clive",
            "Hector Munro",
            "Alexander Burnes"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which of the following princely states was not annexed by the British",
        "answer": "Gwalior",
        "choices": [
            "Gwalior",
            "Sind",
            "Awadh",
            "Satara"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Sind was conquered and annexed by",
        "answer": "Charles Napier",
        "choices": [
            "Charles Napier",
            "Wellington",
            "Sleeman",
            "Lawrence"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The first railway in India was ladi down during the period of",
        "answer": "Dalhousie",
        "choices": [
            "Dalhousie",
            "George Curzon",
            "Wellesly",
            "Lytton"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Queen Victoria was appointed the Empress of India in",
        "answer": 1876,
        "choices": [
            1876,
            1877,
            1858,
            1885
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Viceroy who followd aggressive policy towards Afghanistan was",
        "answer": "Robert Lytton",
        "choices": [
            "Robert Lytton",
            "Richard Bourke - Mayo",
            "Frederick Hamilton - Dufferin",
            "Charles Canning"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which among the following viceroy's period the title of Rai Bahadur and Khan Bhadur began to confer to Indian?",
        "answer": "Robert Lytton",
        "choices": [
            "Robert Lytton",
            "Richard Bourke - Mayo",
            "Frederick Hamilton - Dufferin",
            "George Robinson Ripon"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In 1902 George Curzon appointed the University Commission including two Indian members.Who were they?",
        "answer": "Syed Hussain Bilgrami & Justice Gururdas Banerjeee",
        "choices": [
            "Syed Hussain Bilgrami & Justice Gururdas Banerjeee",
            "Bal Gangadhar Tilak and Surendranath Banerjee",
            "Gopal Krishna Gokhale and Rashbehari Bose",
            "Syed Hussain Bilgrami & Surendranath Banerjee"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In which year was the Indian Universities Act passed by George Curzon?",
        "answer": 1904,
        "choices": [
            1904,
            1901,
            1906,
            1886
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who established Imperial Cadet Corps?",
        "answer": "Charles Curzon",
        "choices": [
            "Charles Curzon",
            "George Robinson Ripon",
            "John Elliot - Minto",
            "Robert Lytton"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In my belief Congress is to tottering to its fails and one of my great ambitions while in India is to assist it to a peaceful demise. Who wrote it",
        "answer": "Charles Curzon",
        "choices": [
            "Charles Curzon",
            "Frederick Hamilton Dufferin",
            "John Elliot - Minto",
            "Robert Lytton"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Muslims, if contented and satisfied would become the greatest bulwark of British power in India, who wrote it?",
        "answer": "William Wilson Hunter",
        "choices": [
            "William Wilson Hunter",
            "Herbert Risley",
            "Henry Noel Brailsford",
            "Robert Lytton"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the founder of Empire in India?",
        "answer": "Robert Clive",
        "choices": [
            "Robert Clive",
            "John Elliot - Minto",
            "Richard Bourke - Mayo",
            "William Henry Sleeman"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who introduced the system of Mahalwari Settlement in Bengal?",
        "answer": "Holt mackenzie",
        "choices": [
            "Holt mackenzie",
            "Charles Cornwallis",
            "Warren Hastings",
            "William Bentinck"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which compensation tax the Indigo farmers were required to pay, if they desired exemption from Indigo cultivation?",
        "answer": "Tawan",
        "choices": [
            "Tawan",
            "Batta",
            "Jaziya",
            "Nazrana"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Permanent Settlement was made with",
        "answer": "Zamindars",
        "choices": [
            "Zamindars",
            "Muqaddamas",
            "Peasants",
            "Village Communities"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which of the following is correct about permanent settlement introduced in Bihar",
        "answer": "The right of ownership of land was made hereditary and transferable for the Zamindars",
        "choices": [
            "The right of ownership of land was made hereditary and transferable for the Zamindars",
            "The Zamindars were deprived of the ownership of the land",
            "Land Revenue was not fixed",
            "Abolition of Zamindari"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In which year the rights of the tenants on land in Bengal and Bihar were given by the Bengal Tenancy Act",
        "answer": 1885,
        "choices": [
            1885,
            1995,
            1875,
            1975
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The system, under which the peasant himself is the owner of the land and is held responsible for the payment of land revenue to the government is known as?",
        "answer": "Ryotwari System",
        "choices": [
            "Ryotwari System",
            "Zamindari System",
            "Mahalwari System",
            "Dahsala System"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Ryotwari system was first implemented in",
        "answer": "Madras",
        "choices": [
            "Madras",
            "Bihar",
            "Bengal",
            "Odisha"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "When was new Enfield Riffle with greased cartridges introduced in the British Indian Army?",
        "answer": "December, 1856",
        "choices": [
            "December, 1856",
            "November, 1856",
            "January, 1857",
            "February, 1857"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which of the following is not a reason for making the sepoys of the East India Company rebellious?",
        "answer": "Inefficiency of the officers",
        "choices": [
            "Inefficiency of the officers",
            "The efforts of the officers of the company to spread Christianity",
            "The order to the sepoys to travel on ships",
            "The stoppage of Bhatta"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Where from the Revolution of 1857 started first?",
        "answer": "Meerut",
        "choices": [
            "Meerut",
            "Lucknow",
            "Allahabad",
            "Jhansi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "At Delhi, during the Revolt of 1857, the nominal and symbolic leadership belonged to the emperor Bahadur Shah, but the real command lay with a court of soldiers headed by",
        "answer": "Bakht Khan",
        "choices": [
            "Bakht Khan",
            "Nana Saheb",
            "Hazrat Mahal",
            "Laxmibai"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The first woman President of the Indian National Congress was",
        "answer": "Annie Besant",
        "choices": [
            "Annie Besant",
            "Sarojini Naidu",
            "Kasturba Gandhi",
            "Aruna Asaf Ali"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The female freedom fighter popularly known as the Grand Old Lady of the Independence Movement was",
        "answer": "Aruna Asaf Ali",
        "choices": [
            "Aruna Asaf Ali",
            "Gulab Kaur",
            "Bishni Devi Shah",
            "Annie Besant"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The revolt of 1857 at Lucknow was led by",
        "answer": "Begum Hazrat Mahal",
        "choices": [
            "Begum Hazrat Mahal",
            "Tatya Tope",
            "Rani Lakshmibai",
            "Nana Saheb"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Where did Satyendra Prasad Sinha resign from the post of Governor in 1921?",
        "answer": "Bihar-Odisha",
        "choices": [
            "Bihar-Odisha",
            "Bengal",
            "Punjab",
            "Madras"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who spearheaded the 1857 Revolt in Bihar?",
        "answer": "Kunwar Singh",
        "choices": [
            "Kunwar Singh",
            "Nana Saheb",
            "Tatya Tope",
            "Maulvi Ahmadullah"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Where did Kunwar Singh join the Rebellion of 1857 against the British?",
        "answer": "Arrah",
        "choices": [
            "Arrah",
            "Patna",
            "Bettiah",
            "Varanasi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who said, Wherever I am, there is Jagadishpur?",
        "answer": "Kunwar Singh",
        "choices": [
            "Kunwar Singh",
            "Amar Singh",
            "Rani Lakshmibai",
            "General Lloyd"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The mutiny of 1857 at Patna was led by a dynamic old person known as",
        "answer": "Kunwar Singh",
        "choices": [
            "Kunwar Singh",
            "Hyder Ali Khan",
            "Judhar Singh",
            "Kusal Singh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The centre of 1857 revolt in Bihar from 15th July 1857 to 20th January 1858 was",
        "answer": "Jagdishpur",
        "choices": [
            "Jagdishpur",
            "Hamirpur",
            "Dheerpur",
            "Rampur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "One of the leaders of the Revolt of 1857 Kunwar Singh was related to which place?",
        "answer": "Jagdishpur",
        "choices": [
            "Jagdishpur",
            "Gwalior",
            "Jhansi",
            "Meerut"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who of the following was the bitterest enemy of the British during the Revolt of 1857?",
        "answer": "Maulavi Ahamadullah Shah",
        "choices": [
            "Maulavi Ahamadullah Shah",
            "Maulavi Imadadullah",
            "Maulana Fazi-i-Haq Khairabadi",
            "Nawab Liaquat Ali"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Revolt of 1857 was witnessed by the poet",
        "answer": "Ghalib",
        "choices": [
            "Ghalib",
            "Zauq",
            "Mir Taqi Mir",
            "Iqbal"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who among the following did not rebel against the British East India Company's control over them?",
        "answer": "Nizam of Hyderabad",
        "choices": [
            "Nizam of Hyderabad",
            "Raja of Vijayanagar",
            "Polygar of Tamil Nadu",
            "Dewan Velu Thampi of Travancore"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which part of Bihar was unaffected with the revolt of 1857?",
        "answer": "Munger",
        "choices": [
            "Munger",
            "Patna",
            "Muzaffarpur",
            "Arrah"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the Governor-General of India in 1857?",
        "answer": "Charles Canning",
        "choices": [
            "Charles Canning",
            "James Andrew - Dalhousie",
            "Richard Wellesley",
            "John Elliot - Minto"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "What was the main cause of the failure of the revolt of 1857?",
        "answer": "Lack of common strategy and central organisation",
        "choices": [
            "Lack of common strategy and central organisation",
            "Lack of Hindu-Muslim Unity",
            "Its effect was within a limited area",
            "Non-participations of Landlords"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who called the revolt of 1857 a conspiracy?",
        "answer": "Sir James Outram and W Taylor",
        "choices": [
            "Sir James Outram and W Taylor",
            "Sir John K",
            "Sir John Lawrence",
            "T R Homes"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "When did Queen Victoria declare the taking over of Indian Administration under British Crown?",
        "answer": "1st November 1858",
        "choices": [
            "1st November 1858",
            "31st Decemeber 1857",
            "6th January 1958",
            "17th November 1859"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which of the following commissions is associated with the army reorganisation after the suppression of the Revolt of 1857?",
        "answer": "Peel Commission",
        "choices": [
            "Peel Commission",
            "Public Service Commission",
            "Hunter Commission",
            "Simon Commission"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "After the revolt of 1857, the British recruited the soldiers from the",
        "answer": "Gurkhas, Sikhs and Punjabis in the North",
        "choices": [
            "Gurkhas, Sikhs and Punjabis in the North",
            "Brahmins of UP & Bihar",
            "Bengalis and Orria's from the East",
            "Madras presidency and Marathas"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The uprising of 1857 was described as the First Indian War of Independence by",
        "answer": "V D Savarkar",
        "choices": [
            "V D Savarkar",
            "Bal Gangadhar Tilak",
            "R C Mazumdar",
            "Dadabhai Naoroji"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Tana Bhagat Movement, a nonviolent movement against British rule, originated among the tribal communities of which Indian State?",
        "answer": "Jharkhand",
        "choices": [
            "Jharkhand",
            "Kerala",
            "Uttar Pradesh",
            "Madras"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Indigo rebellion was about",
        "answer": "the peasant not wanting to grow indigo but being forced to grow at a price that was unacceptable",
        "choices": [
            "the peasant not wanting to grow indigo but being forced to grow at a price that was unacceptable",
            "the peasant not wanting to grow indigo but being forced",
            "the peasant wanting to grow indigo but being forced not to",
            "a protest movement that carried an indigo coloured flag"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who is the author of Neel Darpan a book written on the miserable condition of Indigo farmers?",
        "answer": "Dinbandhu Mitra",
        "choices": [
            "Dinbandhu Mitra",
            "Bankim Chandra Chatterji",
            "Acharya Kripalani",
            "Rabindranath Tagore"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In which month of 1918 was the Champaran Agrarian Act passed against the European Indigo planters?",
        "answer": "March, 1918",
        "choices": [
            "March, 1918",
            "January, 1918",
            "December, 1918",
            "September, 1918"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the bitter critic of Sir Syed Ahmed Khan?",
        "answer": "Jamaluddin Afghani",
        "choices": [
            "Jamaluddin Afghani",
            "C F Andrews",
            "Maulvi Zakaullah",
            "Shibli Nomani"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "What was the purpose of Barhiyataal resistence in Munger?",
        "answer": "Demand of Bakast land restoration",
        "choices": [
            "Demand of Bakast land restoration",
            "Muslim peasants may not be exploited",
            "Abolishment of Zamindari custom",
            "Beginning of class struggle"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Kuka Movement was organised by",
        "answer": "Guru Ram Singh",
        "choices": [
            "Guru Ram Singh",
            "Guru Nanak",
            "Guru Gobind Singh",
            "Guru Ram Das"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who founded the Pagal Panth",
        "answer": "Karam Shah",
        "choices": [
            "Karam Shah",
            "Bulleh Shah",
            "Yaduvendra Singh",
            "Swami Shajananada"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who were the Faraizis?",
        "answer": "Followers of Haji Shariatullah",
        "choices": [
            "Followers of Haji Shariatullah",
            "Followers of Dadu",
            "Followers of the Arya Samaj",
            "Followers of the Muslim League"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who began the Faraizi movement?",
        "answer": "Haji Shariatullah",
        "choices": [
            "Haji Shariatullah",
            "Syed Ahmed",
            "Salimullah",
            "Muhammad Ali Jinnah"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Taiyuni Movement began in opposition of the Faraizi Movement at Dhaka in 1893 was started by",
        "answer": "Maulana Karamat Ali of Jaunpur",
        "choices": [
            "Maulana Karamat Ali of Jaunpur",
            "Syed Amir Ali of Calcutta",
            "Sir Syed Ahmed of Aligarh",
            "Hasn Imam of Patna"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who founded Ramosi Krishak Jatha in Maharashtra?",
        "answer": "Vasudeo Balwant Phadke",
        "choices": [
            "Vasudeo Balwant Phadke",
            "Justice Ranade",
            "Gopal Krishna Gokhale",
            "Jyotiba Phule"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The correct geographical location for the Ramosi Uprising was",
        "answer": "Western Ghats",
        "choices": [
            "Western Ghats",
            "Western India",
            "Eastern India",
            "Eastern Ghats"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Name the tribe that rebelled against the Britishers because human sacrifice system was banned",
        "answer": "Khond",
        "choices": [
            "Khond",
            "Kuki",
            "Oraon",
            "Nackda"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Kol Mutiny of 1831 under Buddho Bhagat took place in which of the following regions?",
        "answer": "Singhbum",
        "choices": [
            "Singhbum",
            "Kutch",
            "Western Ghats",
            "Satara"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Waghera Uprising happened in",
        "answer": "Baroda",
        "choices": [
            "Baroda",
            "Surat",
            "Poona",
            "Calicut"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who were the leaders of Santhal Revolt?",
        "answer": "Sidhu and Kanhu",
        "choices": [
            "Sidhu and Kanhu",
            "Jara Bhagat and Balaram Bhagat",
            "Gaurakshni Bhagat and Keshav Chandra Roy",
            "Shambhumath Pal and Korra Mallaya"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which among the following year Santhal Revolt occurred?",
        "answer": "1855-56 CE",
        "choices": [
            "1855-56 CE",
            "1831-32 CE",
            "1844-46 CE",
            "1851-52 CE"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which British Commander was defeated by the Santhals in 1855?",
        "answer": "Major Burroguh",
        "choices": [
            "Major Burroguh",
            "Captain nek Feville",
            "Lt. Bastain",
            "Colonel White"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Mundas raised revolt in",
        "answer": 1899,
        "choices": [
            1899,
            1888,
            1857,
            1875
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Birsa Munda was considered by his followers as the incarnation of ",
        "answer": "Dharti Abba",
        "choices": [
            "Dharti Abba",
            "Sing Bonga",
            "Mago Manki",
            "Bir Sing"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Ulgulan Revolt was related to",
        "answer": "Birsa Munda",
        "choices": [
            "Birsa Munda",
            "Kachha Nagh",
            "Santhal",
            "Kol"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the leader of Munda rebellion of 1899-1900 CE?",
        "answer": "Birsa Munda",
        "choices": [
            "Birsa Munda",
            "Budha Bhagat",
            "Siddhu",
            "Tilak Manjhi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Birsa Munda was in favour of",
        "answer": "Munda Raj",
        "choices": [
            "Munda Raj",
            "British Raj",
            "Raj of Dikus",
            "Sepration of Jharkhand"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which was the working area of Birsa Munda?",
        "answer": "Ranchi",
        "choices": [
            "Ranchi",
            "Champaran",
            "Alipur",
            "Balia"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In which territory did tribals rebel against the British?",
        "answer": "Bihar",
        "choices": [
            "Bihar",
            "Punjab",
            "Sindh",
            "Kathiwar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Hoz revolt took place during",
        "answer": "1820-21",
        "choices": [
            "1820-21",
            "1620-21",
            "1720-21",
            "1920-21"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Moplah Rebellion of 1921 broke out in",
        "answer": "Kerala",
        "choices": [
            "Kerala",
            "Assam",
            "Punjab",
            "Bengal"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In which year did Charles Wood send his despatch on General Education in India?",
        "answer": 1854,
        "choices": [
            1854,
            1857,
            1848,
            1850
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In which year Mohammedan Anglo-Oriental College at Aligarh was established?",
        "answer": 1877,
        "choices": [
            1877,
            1870,
            1880,
            1890
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "When was the National Council of Education established?",
        "answer": "15th August 1906",
        "choices": [
            "15th August 1906",
            "15th August 1903",
            "15th August 1904",
            "15th August 1905"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "When did the British Government appoint Sadler University Commission for reforms in education?",
        "answer": 1917,
        "choices": [
            1917,
            1919,
            1921,
            1896
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which of the following Indians qualified the Indian Civil Service Exam for the first time in 1863?",
        "answer": "Satyendranath Thakur",
        "choices": [
            "Satyendranath Thakur",
            "Rabindranath Thakur",
            "Debendranath Thakur",
            "Surendranath Thakur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In 1890, the first woman graduate of Calcutta University, who addressed the Congress session was",
        "answer": "Kadambini Ganguly",
        "choices": [
            "Kadambini Ganguly",
            "Sarojini Naidu",
            "Annie Besant",
            "Indira Gandhi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The spiritual side of nationalism was voiced by",
        "answer": "Swami Vivekananda",
        "choices": [
            "Swami Vivekananda",
            "Raja Ram Mohun Roy",
            "Swami Shraddhanand",
            "Swami Shajananada"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who founded the newspaper - The Hindu in 1878, which became influential in shaping public opinion during the Indian national movement?",
        "answer": "G Subramania Iyer",
        "choices": [
            "G Subramania Iyer",
            "Viraraghavachariar",
            "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "Sahajananda Saraswati"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who among the following repealed the Vernacular Press Act of 1878?",
        "answer": "George Robinson - Ripon",
        "choices": [
            "George Robinson - Ripon",
            "Robert Lytton",
            "Charles Curzon",
            "John Elliot - Minto"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who in America started to issue newspaper The Free Hindustan?",
        "answer": "Tarak Nath Das",
        "choices": [
            "Tarak Nath Das",
            "Ram Nath Puri",
            "G D Kumar",
            "Lala Hardayal"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who founded the Amrit Bazar Patrika?",
        "answer": "Shishir Kumar Ghose",
        "choices": [
            "Shishir Kumar Ghose",
            "Harish Chandra Mukherjee",
            "S N Banerjee",
            "Girish Chandra Ghose"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which of the following papers was essentially the mouthpiece of the policies of liberals?",
        "answer": "Leader",
        "choices": [
            "Leader",
            "New India",
            "Young India",
            "Free Press Journal"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which journal was not associated with revolutionary activities?",
        "answer": "Young India",
        "choices": [
            "Young India",
            "Yugantar",
            "Sandhya",
            "Gadar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which of the following newspaper used to be published from Patna?",
        "answer": "The Indian Nation",
        "choices": [
            "The Indian Nation",
            "Punjab Kesari",
            "Prabhakar",
            "Dawn"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Name the editor of nationalist newspaper - Kesari",
        "answer": "Bal Gangadhar Tilak",
        "choices": [
            "Bal Gangadhar Tilak",
            "G Subramania Iyer",
            "Surendranath Banerjee",
            "Gopal Krishna Gokhale"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Name the editor of nationalist newspaper - Bengalee",
        "answer": "Surendranath Banerjee",
        "choices": [
            "Surendranath Banerjee",
            "Ganga Prasad Verma",
            "Bal Gangadhar Tilak",
            "Gopal Krishna Gokhale"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Name the editor of nationalist newspaper - Hindustani",
        "answer": "Ganga Prasad Verma",
        "choices": [
            "Ganga Prasad Verma",
            "Surendranath Banerjee",
            "Bal Gangadhar Tilak",
            "Gopal Krishna Gokhale"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Name the editor of nationalist newspaper - Sudharak",
        "answer": "Gopal Krishna Gokhale",
        "choices": [
            "Gopal Krishna Gokhale",
            "Ganga Prasad Verma",
            "G Subramania Iyer",
            "Surendranath Banerjee"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Name the editor of nationalist newspaper - The Mahratta",
        "answer": "Bal Gangadhar Tilak",
        "choices": [
            "Bal Gangadhar Tilak",
            "G Subramania Iyer",
            "Surendranath Banerjee",
            "Ganga Prasad Verma"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which of the following was not a nationalist newspaper",
        "answer": "The Times of India",
        "choices": [
            "The Times of India",
            "Bengalee",
            "The Mahratta",
            "The Hindu"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The nationalist daily newpaper - Then Indian Nation started its publication in",
        "answer": 1931,
        "choices": [
            1931,
            1930,
            1940,
            1947
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which category of population was least attracted to Religious reform movements of the nineteenth century?",
        "answer": "Poor Ordinariness Class",
        "choices": [
            "Poor Ordinariness Class",
            "Intellectuals",
            "Urban Upper Castes",
            "Liberal Princes"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the father of the Indian Renaissance movement?",
        "answer": "Raja Ram Mohan Roy",
        "choices": [
            "Raja Ram Mohan Roy",
            "Bal Gangadhar Tilak",
            "Dayanand Saraswati",
            "Shraddhanand"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who among the following was the founder of Atmiya Sabha?",
        "answer": "Raja Ram Mohan Roy",
        "choices": [
            "Raja Ram Mohan Roy",
            "Swami Dayanand Saraswati",
            "Swami Vivekanand",
            "Aurobindo Ghosh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Brahmo Samaj was founded in the year of",
        "answer": 1828,
        "choices": [
            1828,
            1827,
            1829,
            1843
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The best representative of Neo-Hindustan in the second half of the 19th century was",
        "answer": "Swami Vivekananda",
        "choices": [
            "Swami Vivekananda",
            "Ramkrishna Paramhans",
            "Bankim Chandra Chatterji",
            "Raja Ram Mohan Roy"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who among the following participated in the parliament of Religions held at Chicago in 1893?",
        "answer": "Swami Vivekananda",
        "choices": [
            "Swami Vivekananda",
            "Swami Dayanand Saraswati",
            "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "Raja Ram Mohan Roy"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Swami Vivekananda established Ramakrishna Mission in the year",
        "answer": 1897,
        "choices": [
            1897,
            1891,
            1861,
            1893
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was Sharadamani",
        "answer": "wife of Ramakrishna Paramhansa",
        "choices": [
            "wife of Ramakrishna Paramhansa",
            "Wife of Raja Ram Mohan Roy",
            "Mother of Vivekananda",
            "Daughter of Keshab Chandra Sen"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Dayanand Saraswati founded",
        "answer": "Arya Samaj",
        "choices": [
            "Arya Samaj",
            "Brahmo Samaj",
            "Prathana Samaj",
            "Bhaujan Samaj"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who established the Arya Samaj",
        "answer": "Swami Dayanand Saraswati",
        "choices": [
            "Swami Dayanand Saraswati",
            "Swami Vivekanand",
            "Joytirao Phule",
            "Ishwar Chandra Vidyasagar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who among the following gave the slogan - India for the Indians?",
        "answer": "Swami Dayanand Saraswati",
        "choices": [
            "Swami Dayanand Saraswati",
            "Swami Vivekanand",
            "H N Kunzru",
            "Ishwar Chandra Vidyasagar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Satyarth Prakash was written by",
        "answer": "Swami Dayanand Saraswati",
        "choices": [
            "Swami Dayanand Saraswati",
            "Swami Vivekanand",
            "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "Ishwar Chandra Vidyasagar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the founder of Prarthana Samaj",
        "answer": "Atmaram Pandurang",
        "choices": [
            "Atmaram Pandurang",
            "Jyotirao Phule",
            "Gopal Hari Deshmukh",
            "Mahatma Gandhi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In 1873 who founded Satya Shodhak Samaj?",
        "answer": "Jyotirao Phule",
        "choices": [
            "Jyotirao Phule",
            "Atmaram Pandurang",
            "Gopal Hari Deshmukh",
            "Naoroji Furdunji"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who established Rehnumai Mazdayasan Sabha",
        "answer": "Naoroji Furdunji",
        "choices": [
            "Naoroji Furdunji",
            "Jyotirao Phule",
            "Atmaram Pandurang",
            "Gopal Hari Deshmukh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which social reformer was called Lokhitwadi?",
        "answer": "Gopal Hari Deshmukh",
        "choices": [
            "Gopal Hari Deshmukh",
            "Gopal Krishna Gokhale",
            "Jayaprakash Narayan",
            "Karpuri Thakur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who declared Sati illegal?",
        "answer": "William Bentinck",
        "choices": [
            "William Bentinck",
            "Warren Hastings",
            "Charles Curzon",
            "Charles Cornwallis"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "When was the Prohibition of Sati Act passed in India?",
        "answer": 1829,
        "choices": [
            1829,
            1830,
            1831,
            1836
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which of the following inscriptions mentions the instance of widow burning (Sati)?",
        "answer": "Eran Pillar Inscription of Bhanugupta",
        "choices": [
            "Eran Pillar Inscription of Bhanugupta",
            "Eran Pillar Inscription of Budhagupta",
            "Eran Stone Inscription of Samudragupta",
            "Eran Boar Inscription of Toramana"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who founded the Theosophical Society?",
        "answer": "Helena Petrovna Blavatsky",
        "choices": [
            "Helena Petrovna Blavatsky",
            "Raja Ram Mohan Roy",
            "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "Swami Vivekanand"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who demanded the right to enter temples that caused a terrible riot in Tirunelveli in 1899?",
        "answer": "Nadars",
        "choices": [
            "Nadars",
            "Okalinga",
            "Mahar",
            "Pali"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the founder of the Indian Association in 1876?",
        "answer": "Surendranath Banerjee",
        "choices": [
            "Surendranath Banerjee",
            "Chittaranjan Das",
            "Arvind Ghosh",
            "Dadabhai Naoroji"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The most important of the pre-Congress Nationalist Organisation was the",
        "answer": "Indian Association of Calcutta",
        "choices": [
            "Indian Association of Calcutta",
            "Young Bengal Association",
            "East India Association",
            "Bengal British India Society"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In which year Surendra Nath Banerjee was eliminated from Indian Civil Services?",
        "answer": 1874,
        "choices": [
            1874,
            1892,
            1885,
            1877
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In which year Surendra Nath Banerjee founded the Indian Association in Kolkata",
        "answer": 1876,
        "choices": [
            1876,
            1870,
            1885,
            1884
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the first Indian to resist the political reforms?",
        "answer": "Raja Ram Mohan Roy",
        "choices": [
            "Raja Ram Mohan Roy",
            "Dadabhai Naoroji",
            "Surendranath Banerjee",
            "Bal Gangadhar Tilak"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Madras Mahajan Sabha was established in the year",
        "answer": 1884,
        "choices": [
            1884,
            1874,
            1881,
            1882
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Madras Mahajan Sabha was established by",
        "answer": "M. Veeraraghavachariar",
        "choices": [
            "M. Veeraraghavachariar",
            "Mahadev Govind Ranade",
            "Surendranath Banerjee",
            "Womesh Chunder Bonerjee"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Poona Sarvajanik Sabha was founded in",
        "answer": 1870,
        "choices": [
            1870,
            1874,
            1881,
            1882
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Poona Sarvajanik Sabha was founded by",
        "answer": "Mahadev Govind Ranade",
        "choices": [
            "Mahadev Govind Ranade",
            "M. Veeraraghavachariar",
            "Surendranath Banerjee",
            "Womesh Chunder Bonerjee"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Bombay Presidency Association was founded in",
        "answer": 1885,
        "choices": [
            1885,
            1870,
            1884,
            1876
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who among the following was not a founder of Bombay Presidency Association",
        "answer": "Womesh Chunder Bonerjee",
        "choices": [
            "Womesh Chunder Bonerjee",
            "Pherozeshah Mehta",
            "Kashinath Trimbak Telang",
            "Badruddin Tayabji"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Indian National Congress was founded by",
        "answer": "Allan Octavian Hume",
        "choices": [
            "Allan Octavian Hume",
            "Surendranath Banerjee",
            "Womesh Chunder Bonerjee",
            "Annie Besant"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The founder of the Indian National Congress was a",
        "answer": "Civil Servant",
        "choices": [
            "Civil Servant",
            "Scientist",
            "Social Worker",
            "Commander"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "When was the Indian National Congress set up?",
        "answer": 1885,
        "choices": [
            1885,
            1884,
            1886,
            1887
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "How many representatives took part in the first session of the Indian National Congress?",
        "answer": "72 delegates",
        "choices": [
            "72 delegates",
            "62 delegates",
            "82 delegates",
            "52 delegates"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The first conference of Indian National Congress was held at",
        "answer": "Mumbai",
        "choices": [
            "Mumbai",
            "Pune",
            "Kolkata",
            "Lahore"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the first muslim President of the Indian National Congress?",
        "answer": "Badruddin Tyabji",
        "choices": [
            "Badruddin Tyabji",
            "Zakir Hussain",
            "Hakim Ajmal Khan",
            "R A Kidwani"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The precursor of Indian National Congress was",
        "answer": "Indian National Union",
        "choices": [
            "Indian National Union",
            "British Indian Association",
            "Indian Association",
            "Indian League"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "How many muslim delegates participated in the Second Convention of the Indian National Congress?",
        "answer": 33,
        "choices": [
            33,
            41,
            30,
            2
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The second session of the Indian National Congress was presided over by",
        "answer": "Dadabhai Naoroji",
        "choices": [
            "Dadabhai Naoroji",
            "Ganesh Agarkar",
            "Surendranath Banerjee",
            "Pherozeshah Mehta"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the second muslim President of the Indian National Congress?",
        "answer": "Rahimtulla Mahomed Sayani",
        "choices": [
            "Rahimtulla Mahomed Sayani",
            "Zakir Hussain",
            "Badruddin Tyabji",
            "Maulana Abul Kalam Azad"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the first woman President of the Indian National Congress?",
        "answer": "Annie Besant",
        "choices": [
            "Annie Besant",
            "Sarojini Naidu",
            "Kadambini Ganguly",
            "Kasturba Gandhi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the first Indian woman President of the Indian National Congress?",
        "answer": "Sarojini Naidu",
        "choices": [
            "Sarojini Naidu",
            "Annie Besant",
            "Kadambini Ganguly",
            "Sucheta Kriplani"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "At which place was the 27th session of the Indian National Congress held?",
        "answer": "Bankipur",
        "choices": [
            "Bankipur",
            "Ramgarh",
            "Gaya",
            "Bhagalpur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "At which of the following sessions of the Indian National Congress did the Champaran trouble come up for discussion?",
        "answer": "Lucknow, 1916",
        "choices": [
            "Lucknow, 1916",
            "Calcutta, 1911",
            "Bankipur, 1912",
            "Ramgarh, 1940"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who said - Sawaraj is my birthright and I shall have it?",
        "answer": "Bal Gangadhar Tilak",
        "choices": [
            "Bal Gangadhar Tilak",
            "Bipan Chandra Pal",
            "Aurobindo Ghosh",
            "Subhash Chandra Bose"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who said - The basic cause of problems facing Bharat is the neglect of its national identity?",
        "answer": "Deen Dayal Upadhyay",
        "choices": [
            "Deen Dayal Upadhyay",
            "Keshav Baliram Hedgewar",
            "Madhav Sadashiv Golwalkar",
            "Karpoori Thakur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Lucknow Pact took place in which year",
        "answer": 1916,
        "choices": [
            1916,
            1915,
            1917,
            1912
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Remember once again, now that this flag is unfurled, it must not be lowered as long as a single Indian, man, woman or child lives in India, who said this?",
        "answer": "Jawaharlal Nehru in Lahore",
        "choices": [
            "Jawaharlal Nehru in Lahore",
            "Gandhi in Gujarat",
            "Surendranath Banerjee in Bengal",
            "Subhash Chandra Bose in Singapore"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who said that Congress Movement was neither inspired by the people, nor devised or planned by them?",
        "answer": "Lala Lajpat Rai",
        "choices": [
            "Lala Lajpat Rai",
            "Syed Ahmed",
            "Frederick Hamilton - Dufferin",
            "George Curzon"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the President of the Patna Session of Indian National Congress held in 1912?",
        "answer": "Raghunath Narsinha Mudholkar",
        "choices": [
            "Raghunath Narsinha Mudholkar",
            "Madan Mohan Malviya",
            "Chittaranjan Das",
            "Ambica Charan Mazumdar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the President of the Gaya Session of Indian National Congress held in 1922?",
        "answer": "Chittaranjan Das",
        "choices": [
            "Chittaranjan Das",
            "Surendranath Banerjee",
            "Rajendra Prasad",
            "Raghunath Narsinha Mudholkar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which tribe of Bihar attended Gaya Session of Congress?",
        "answer": "Oraon",
        "choices": [
            "Oraon",
            "Santhal",
            "Sannyasi",
            "Munda"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Shubhas Chandra Bose became the President of the Indian National Congress in Tripuri Session by defeating",
        "answer": "Pattabhi Sitaramayya",
        "choices": [
            "Pattabhi Sitaramayya",
            "Rash Behari Bose",
            "Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Rajendra Prasad"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which Raja rendered a very valuable assistance to the Indian Natioanal Congress for holding is Fourth Session at Allahabad in 1888?",
        "answer": "Raja of Darbhanga",
        "choices": [
            "Raja of Darbhanga",
            "Raja of Benaras",
            "Raja of Jagdishpur",
            "Raja of Bhinga"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Sardar Udham Singh killed whom?",
        "answer": "Micheal O'Dwyar",
        "choices": [
            "Micheal O'Dwyar",
            "Reginald Dyer",
            "Curzon Wyllie",
            "Saunders"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The protest method of moderate leaders of the Congress was?",
        "answer": "Constitutional Agitation",
        "choices": [
            "Constitutional Agitation",
            "Non-Cooperation",
            "Passive Resistance",
            "Civil Disobedience"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Most of the moderate leader hailed from",
        "answer": "Urban Areas",
        "choices": [
            "Urban Areas",
            "Rural Areas",
            "Both Rural & Urban Areas",
            "Punjab"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which one of the following was not an extremist?",
        "answer": "Gopal Krishna Gokhale",
        "choices": [
            "Gopal Krishna Gokhale",
            "Bal Gangadhar Tilak",
            "Udham Singh",
            "Madan Lal"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who established the Servants of India Society?",
        "answer": "Gopal Krishna Gokhale",
        "choices": [
            "Gopal Krishna Gokhale",
            "Lala Lajpat Rai",
            "Bipin Chandra Pal",
            "Bhagat Singh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Indian National Movement came to be dominated by the extremists after",
        "answer": 1906,
        "choices": [
            1906,
            1909,
            1914,
            1919
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which one of the following leaders belonged to the Extremist wing of the Congress?",
        "answer": "Aurobindo Ghosh",
        "choices": [
            "Aurobindo Ghosh",
            "Dadabhai Naoroji",
            "Gopal Krishna Gokhale",
            "Surendranath Banerjee"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who among the following was not known as a moderate in the National Movement?",
        "answer": "Bal Gangadhar Tilak",
        "choices": [
            "Bal Gangadhar Tilak",
            "Dadabhai Naoroji",
            "Gopal Krishna Gokhale",
            "Mahadev Govind Ranade"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who is popularly known as Sher-e-Punjab?",
        "answer": "Lala Lajpat Rai",
        "choices": [
            "Lala Lajpat Rai",
            "Bhagat Singh",
            "Rajguru",
            "Udham Singh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In 1908, Bal Gangadhar Tilak was imprisoned for",
        "answer": "6 years",
        "choices": [
            "6 years",
            "5 years",
            "7 years",
            "8 years"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who said about Bengal partition, The partition announcement fell like a bomb shell?",
        "answer": "Surendranath Banerjee",
        "choices": [
            "Surendranath Banerjee",
            "Gopal Krishna Gokhale",
            "Bipin Chandra Pal",
            "Chittaranjan Das"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Bal Gangadhar Tilak came to be known as Lokmanya Tilak when",
        "answer": "The Government accused him in the Rand Murder case",
        "choices": [
            "The Government accused him in the Rand Murder case",
            "He started the Shivaji and Ganpati festivals",
            "He started a popular newspaper",
            "He became a popular teacher"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who founded Abhinav Bharat Society in 1906 in London?",
        "answer": "Vinayak Damodar Savarkar",
        "choices": [
            "Vinayak Damodar Savarkar",
            "Shyamji Krishna Verma",
            "Sohan Singh",
            "Pandurang Mahadev Bapat"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who established a branch of Anushilan Samiti at Patna in 1913?",
        "answer": "Sachindra Nath Sanyal",
        "choices": [
            "Sachindra Nath Sanyal",
            "Rewati Nag",
            "Yadunath Sarkar",
            "Mazharul Haque"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Anushilan Samiti was",
        "answer": "a revolutionary organisation",
        "choices": [
            "a revolutionary organisation",
            "dedicated to the upliftment of women",
            "promoting widow remarriage",
            "interested in labour welfare"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the founder of Swadesh Bandhav Samiti?",
        "answer": "Ashwini Kumar Dutta",
        "choices": [
            "Ashwini Kumar Dutta",
            "Prafulla Chaki",
            "Vinayak Damodar Savarkar",
            "Gopal Krishna Gokhale"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "When did the attempt of murder of Kingsford was made at Muzaffarpur, Bihar?",
        "answer": 1908,
        "choices": [
            1908,
            1909,
            1907,
            1911
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who among the following was hanged on the charge of Muzaffarpur Bomb Case?",
        "answer": "Khudiram Bose",
        "choices": [
            "Khudiram Bose",
            "Prafulla Chaki",
            "Batukeshwar Dutt",
            "Rajendra Lahiri"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In which place Khudiram Bose tried to kill Kingsford?",
        "answer": "Muzaffarpur",
        "choices": [
            "Muzaffarpur",
            "Gaya",
            "Darbhanga",
            "Patna"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was given life punishment for the murder of Colonel Wyllie?",
        "answer": "Madan Lal Dhingra",
        "choices": [
            "Madan Lal Dhingra",
            "Udham Singh",
            "Bhagat Singh",
            "Manmathanath"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Non-Cooperation Movement was suspended in",
        "answer": 1922,
        "choices": [
            1922,
            1921,
            1923,
            1924
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which year Hindustan Republican Association was set up",
        "answer": 1924,
        "choices": [
            1924,
            1920,
            1928,
            1930
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who penned the following lines? Sarfaroshi ki tamanna ab hamare dil me hai dekhna hai zor kitna baju-e-qatil me hai.",
        "answer": "Bismil Azimabadi",
        "choices": [
            "Bismil Azimabadi",
            "Rajguru",
            "Bhagat Singh",
            "Azad"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which revolutionaries were hanged in the Kakori Train Robbery Case?",
        "answer": "Ram Prasad Bismil and Ashfaqulla",
        "choices": [
            "Ram Prasad Bismil and Ashfaqulla",
            "Vinayak Damodar Savarkar and Vasudev Chapekar",
            "Prafulla Chandra Chaki and Khudiram Bose",
            "Surya Sen and Udham Singh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who among the following was not associated with the Kakori train robbery case?",
        "answer": "Sukhdev",
        "choices": [
            "Sukhdev",
            "Ram Prasad Bismil",
            "Ashfaqulla Khan",
            "Roshan Singh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "How old was Bhagat Singh when he threw a bomb in the assembly in protest against the government?",
        "answer": "a little more than 21 years",
        "choices": [
            "a little more than 21 years",
            "21 years",
            "25 years",
            "a little more than 25 years"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "One of the founder leaders of Hindustan Socialist Republican Army was",
        "answer": "Bhagat Singh",
        "choices": [
            "Bhagat Singh",
            "Bhimrao Ambedkar",
            "Subhash Chandra Bose",
            "Jai Prakash Narayan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who gave the Inquilab Zindabad slogan?",
        "answer": "Bhagat Singh",
        "choices": [
            "Bhagat Singh",
            "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "Iqbal",
            "Subhash Chandra Bose"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Bhagat Singh, Rajguru and Sukhdev were executed on",
        "answer": "23rd March 1931",
        "choices": [
            "23rd March 1931",
            "23rd March 1932",
            "23rd March 1933",
            "23rd March 1934"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Chittagong Armoury raid had been planned by",
        "answer": "Surya Sen",
        "choices": [
            "Surya Sen",
            "Chandan Dutta",
            "Jatin Das",
            "Vidhan Ghosh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who propounded the doctrine of Passive Resistance",
        "answer": "Aurobindo Ghosh",
        "choices": [
            "Aurobindo Ghosh",
            "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "Bipin Chandra Pal",
            "Bal Gangadhar Tilak"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "What was the slogan of the Bolsheviks during the 1917 Revolution?",
        "answer": "Peace, Land, Bread",
        "choices": [
            "Peace, Land, Bread",
            "Workers of the world, Unite",
            "Liberty, Equality, Fraternity",
            "Freedom and Justice"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the founder of the India House in London?",
        "answer": "Shyamji Krishnavarma",
        "choices": [
            "Shyamji Krishnavarma",
            "Rash Behari Bose",
            "Ramchandra",
            "Taraknath Das"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Ghadar Party was established in the year?",
        "answer": 1913,
        "choices": [
            1913,
            1907,
            1917,
            1920
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Where was the Ghadar Party established?",
        "answer": "United States of America",
        "choices": [
            "United States of America",
            "Germany",
            "France",
            "England"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "What was the cause of outbreak of Ghadar Revolution",
        "answer": "Beginning of first World War",
        "choices": [
            "Beginning of first World War",
            "Arresting of Lala Hardayal",
            "Kamagatamaru incident",
            "Hanging of Kartar Singh Sarabha"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Interim government under the leadership of Raja Mahendra Pratap Singh was founded in Kabul with the support of Germany during",
        "answer": "First World War",
        "choices": [
            "First World War",
            "Second World War",
            "Ghadar Movement",
            "Swadeshi Movement"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who is regarded as the Mother of Indian Revolution?",
        "answer": "Bhikaiji Rustom Cama",
        "choices": [
            "Bhikaiji Rustom Cama",
            "Annie Besant",
            "Sarojini Naidu",
            "Rama Bai"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Where did Madam Cama unfurl India's tricolour flag of freedom?",
        "answer": "Stuttgart, Germany",
        "choices": [
            "Stuttgart, Germany",
            "Paris, France",
            "London, England",
            "Geneva, Switzerland"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who called for a Total Revolution at Gandhi Maidan, Patna?",
        "answer": "Jayaprakash Narayan",
        "choices": [
            "Jayaprakash Narayan",
            "Rajendra Prasad",
            "Raj Kumar Shukla",
            "Karpoori Thakur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Swadeshi and Boycott were adopted as the methods of struggle for the first time during the",
        "answer": "Partition of Bengal",
        "choices": [
            "Partition of Bengal",
            "Home Rule Movement",
            "Visit of Simon Commission ",
            "Arrival of Mahatma Gandhi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In which place was the organisation named Golden League formed to work for boycott and the Swadeshi Movement?",
        "answer": "Deoghar",
        "choices": [
            "Deoghar",
            "Muzaffarpur",
            "Patna",
            "Ranchi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The declaration of Partition of Bengal was done on",
        "answer": "19th July 1905",
        "choices": [
            "19th July 1905",
            "16th October 1905",
            "15th August 1905",
            "7th August 1905"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which movement started after the Partition of Bengal?",
        "answer": "Swadeshi Movement",
        "choices": [
            "Swadeshi Movement",
            "Civil Disobedience",
            "Quit India Movement",
            "Non-Cooperation Movement"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Name the viceroy of Indian concerned with Bengal partition",
        "answer": "Charles Curzon",
        "choices": [
            "Charles Curzon",
            "John Elliot - Minto",
            "Robert Lytton",
            "Charles Hardinge"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Bengal was partitioned in 1905, but due to opposition it was annulled in",
        "answer": 1911,
        "choices": [
            1911,
            1906,
            1916,
            1909
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which of the following classes was mainly unaffected of Swadeshi Movement of 1905?",
        "answer": "Farmers & Muslims",
        "choices": [
            "Farmers & Muslims",
            "Women",
            "Intellectuals",
            "Women & Farmers"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which of the following leaders presided over Congress Session at Calcutta in 1906?",
        "answer": "Dadabhai Naoroji",
        "choices": [
            "Dadabhai Naoroji",
            "Bal Gangadhar Tilak",
            "Gopal Krishna Gokhale",
            "Aurobindo Ghosh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "At the Calcutta Session of the Indian National Congress held in 1906, the Flag of Swaraj for India was unfurled by",
        "answer": "Dadabhai Naoroji",
        "choices": [
            "Dadabhai Naoroji",
            "Allan Octavian Hume",
            "Gopal Krishna Gokhale",
            "Bal Gangadhar Tilak"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "First Indian elected to the British House of Commons was Dadabhai Naoroji who contested on the ticket of ",
        "answer": "Liberal Party",
        "choices": [
            "Liberal Party",
            "Labour Party",
            "Conservative Party",
            "Communist Party"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was not among the founders of All India Muslim League?",
        "answer": "Muhammad Ali Jinnah",
        "choices": [
            "Muhammad Ali Jinnah",
            "Nawab Salimullah",
            "Nawab Moshin-ul-Mulk",
            "Agha Khan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Muslim deputation met Minto in 1906 at Shimla and pleaded for",
        "answer": "Separate electorate for Muslims",
        "choices": [
            "Separate electorate for Muslims",
            "a composite electorate",
            "higher representation to the Hindus",
            "Special representation to Muslim by nomination"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who propounded the two-nation theory prior to the Pakistan Resolution of the Muslim League?",
        "answer": "Syed Ahmad Khan",
        "choices": [
            "Syed Ahmad Khan",
            "Muhammad Iqbal",
            "Liaquat Ali Khan",
            "Muhammad Ali Jinnah"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Whom did Rajendra Prasad considered as the father of Pakistan?",
        "answer": "Gilbert Elliot - Minto",
        "choices": [
            "Gilbert Elliot - Minto",
            "Muhammad Ali Jinnah",
            "Louis Mountbatten",
            "Liaquat Ali Khan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Bihar became a separate state during the British rule in the year?",
        "answer": 1912,
        "choices": [
            1912,
            1905,
            1936,
            1946
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who earned the title of Recruiting Sergeant of the British for this support to the government during First World War?",
        "answer": "Mahatma Gandhi",
        "choices": [
            "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "Motilal Nehru",
            "Madan Mohan Malviya",
            "Gopal Krishna Gokhale"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who among the following did not contribute to Home Rule League?",
        "answer": "T S Alcott",
        "choices": [
            "T S Alcott",
            "Bal Gangadhar Tilak",
            "Annie Besant",
            "S Subramaniam Iyer"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In which conference could the Home-Rule supporters demonstrate their political power successfully?",
        "answer": "Lucknow Conference of Congress in 1916",
        "choices": [
            "Lucknow Conference of Congress in 1916",
            "All India Trade Union Conference held at Bombay in 1920",
            "First Uttar Pradesh Association held in 1918",
            "Joint AITUC and NTU sabha at Nagpur in 1938"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Home Rule Movement was symbol of starting a new phase of freedom movement in India because",
        "answer": "it put a perfect project for the self-Government before the nation",
        "choices": [
            "it put a perfect project for the self-Government before the nation",
            "Leadership of the movement came in the hands of Gandhiji",
            "Hindus and Muslims started to struggle jointly",
            "It established co-ordination between extremists and moderates"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In which of the following colleges, Gandhiji studied?",
        "answer": "Samaldas College, Bhavnagar",
        "choices": [
            "Samaldas College, Bhavnagar",
            "Dharmendrasinji College, Rajkot",
            "Gujarat College, Ahmedabad",
            "Bahauddin College, Junagadh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "To sort out whose legal problem was Mahatma Gandhi invited in South Africa in 1893?",
        "answer": "Dada Abdullah of Gujarat",
        "choices": [
            "Dada Abdullah of Gujarat",
            "Sheikh Abdullah of Kashmir",
            "Titu Mir of Bengal",
            "Imdad Imam of Bihar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which of the following was Gandhiji's first Satyagraha Movement in India in which he used Civil Disobedience?",
        "answer": "Champaran",
        "choices": [
            "Champaran",
            "Kheda",
            "Ahmedabad",
            "Rowlatt"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In response to the mass agitation of the Champaran Movement, the British Government took which step to address the issue?",
        "answer": "Instituted the Champaran Agrarian Committee",
        "choices": [
            "Instituted the Champaran Agrarian Committee",
            "Appointed Mahatma Gandhi as the Governor of Champaran",
            "Enforced strict curfew and imposed Martial Law in the region",
            "Declared Champaran as an independent State"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The cook from Bihar who saved Mahatma Gandhi's life from a murder attempt by food poisoning in 1917 was",
        "answer": "Batak Mian",
        "choices": [
            "Batak Mian",
            "Rajendra Prasad",
            "Raj Kumar Shukla",
            "Erwin"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In which of the following movements did Mahatma Gandhi make the first use of the hunger strike as a weapon?",
        "answer": "Ahmedabad Strike",
        "choices": [
            "Ahmedabad Strike",
            "Non-Cooperation Movement",
            "Bardoli Satyagraha",
            "Rowlatt Satyagraha"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In which of the following Satyagraha movements, did Gandhiji not participate directly?",
        "answer": "Vaikom Satyagraha",
        "choices": [
            "Vaikom Satyagraha",
            "Rajkot Satyagraha",
            "Khera Satyagraha",
            "Non-Cooperation Movement"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who among the following capitalists served as an AICC treasurer for many years and went to Jail in 1930?",
        "answer": "Jamnalal Bajaj",
        "choices": [
            "Jamnalal Bajaj",
            "G D Birla",
            "J R D Tata",
            "Balchand Hirachand"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Gandhi's close English compatriot during the Freedom movement was",
        "answer": "Charles Freer Andrews",
        "choices": [
            "Charles Freer Andrews",
            "Thomas Moore",
            "Allan Octavian Hume",
            "William Wavell"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the political guru of Mahatma Gandhi?",
        "answer": "Gopal Krishna Gokhale",
        "choices": [
            "Gopal Krishna Gokhale",
            "Dadabhai Naoroji",
            "Mahadev Govind Ranade",
            "Surendranath Banerjee"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who participated in Satyagraha started by Gandhiji at Ahmedabad in 1917-18?",
        "answer": "Industrial Workers",
        "choices": [
            "Industrial Workers",
            "Cultivators Class",
            "Public",
            "Middle Class"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who drew Gandhiji's attention to the plight of Indigo peasants in Champaran?",
        "answer": "Raj Kumar Shukla",
        "choices": [
            "Raj Kumar Shukla",
            "Rajendra Prasad",
            "Anugrah Narayan Sinha",
            "Acharya Kriplani"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "How much part of the land was kept in trust for the cultivation of indigo in Bihar under Tinkathiya system?",
        "answer": "3 of 20 Kattha",
        "choices": [
            "3 of 20 Kattha",
            "1 of 10 Kattha",
            "1 of 3 Kattha",
            "3 of 25 Kattha"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "At which place of Bihar, Gandhiji started Satyagraha movement for the first time in India?",
        "answer": "Champaran",
        "choices": [
            "Champaran",
            "Madhubani",
            "Gaya",
            "Patna"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The person not connected with Champarana Movement was",
        "answer": "Jai Prakash Narayan",
        "choices": [
            "Jai Prakash Narayan",
            "Rajendra Prasad",
            "Anugrah Narayan Sinha",
            "Jivatram Bhagwandas Kriplani"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In which Farmer's Movement did Mahatma Gandhi participate first of all?",
        "answer": "Champaran",
        "choices": [
            "Champaran",
            "Kheda",
            "Bardoli",
            "Baroda"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the National Leader of Champaran Indigo movement?",
        "answer": "Mahatma Gandhi",
        "choices": [
            "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "Birsa Munda",
            "Baba Ramchandra",
            "Ram Singh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Nai-Dhobi Band was a form of Social boycott in 1919 which",
        "answer": "was started by the farmers of Pratapgarh district",
        "choices": [
            "was started by the farmers of Pratapgarh district",
            "was a movement started by saints for the emancipation of the people lower classes",
            "was a step against contractors of lower castes by landlords",
            "was a movement against contractors by lower castes"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Sarabandi Campaign of 1922 was led by",
        "answer": "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
        "choices": [
            "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
            "Chittaranjan Das",
            "Rajendra Prasad",
            "Lala Lajpat Rai"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Swami Sahajananda was related to which of the following?",
        "answer": "Peasant Movement in Bihar",
        "choices": [
            "Peasant Movement in Bihar",
            "Tribal Movement in Bihar",
            "Labour Movement in Bihar",
            "Caste Movement in Bihar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "What was the aim of Eka Movement in Oudh?",
        "answer": "To protect rights of peasants agianst landlord oppression",
        "choices": [
            "To protect rights of peasants agianst landlord oppression",
            "To stop to give rent to the Government",
            "To protect the rights of landlords ",
            "End of Satyagraha"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Eka Movement was launched in the rural areas of which region?",
        "answer": "Awadh",
        "choices": [
            "Awadh",
            "Bihar",
            "Punjab",
            "Bengal"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Swami Sahajanand Saraswati published a journal named",
        "answer": "Hunkar",
        "choices": [
            "Hunkar",
            "Jankranti",
            "Krishak Samachar",
            "Vidrohi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Akhil Bhartiya Kisan Congress also known as All India Kisan Sabha was founded in ",
        "answer": 1936,
        "choices": [
            1936,
            1939,
            1942,
            1945
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was elected the first president of All India Kisan Sabha at Lucknow in 1936?",
        "answer": "Swami Sahajanand Saraswati",
        "choices": [
            "Swami Sahajanand Saraswati",
            "N G Ranga",
            "E M S Namboodripad",
            "Acharya Narendra Dev"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Where was the first All India Kisan Maha Sabha formed?",
        "answer": "Lucknow",
        "choices": [
            "Lucknow",
            "Allahabad",
            "Kolkata",
            "Patna"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Tebhaga Movement was started in 1946 from Bengal under leadership of",
        "answer": "Kisan Sabha",
        "choices": [
            "Kisan Sabha",
            "Muslim League",
            "Indian National Congress",
            "Trade Union"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Congress took a critical stand over the Montford Reforms in 1918, which led to break up with the old moderate remnants (Sapru, Jayakar, Chintamani) who formed the ",
        "answer": "Indian National Liberal Federation",
        "choices": [
            "Indian National Liberal Federation",
            "Servants of India Society",
            "Swaraj Party",
            "Janta Dal"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the first President of All India Trade Union Congress?",
        "answer": "Lala Lajpat Rai",
        "choices": [
            "Lala Lajpat Rai",
            "B T Ranade",
            "Satya Bhakta",
            "N M Joshi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "When was All India Trade Union Congress established in Bombay?",
        "answer": 1920,
        "choices": [
            1920,
            1925,
            1929,
            1935
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the first Indian to be the member of Communist International?",
        "answer": "Manabendra Nath Roy",
        "choices": [
            "Manabendra Nath Roy",
            "Muzaffar Ahmad",
            "S A Dange",
            "Lala Lajpat Rai"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The revolutionary phase of the trade union movement in India was",
        "answer": "1926-39",
        "choices": [
            "1926-39",
            "1939-45",
            "1918-26",
            "1914-18"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "When was the Rowlatt Act passed?",
        "answer": 1919,
        "choices": [
            1919,
            1909,
            1930,
            1942
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which of the following Acts enabled the British Government to suspend the right of Habeas Corpus?",
        "answer": "The Rowlatt Act, 1919",
        "choices": [
            "The Rowlatt Act, 1919",
            "The Indian Councils Act, 1909",
            "The Indian Councils Act, 1919",
            "The Government of India Act, 1935"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Jallianwala Bagh Massacre happened in the context of which Gandhian Satyagraha?",
        "answer": "Rowlatt Satyagraha",
        "choices": [
            "Rowlatt Satyagraha",
            "Swadeshi Satyagraha",
            "Bardoli Satyagraha",
            "Individual Satyagraha"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Indian National Congress opposed the Rowlatt Act because it aimed",
        "answer": "to limit the individual liberty",
        "choices": [
            "to limit the individual liberty",
            "to ban Indian National Congress",
            "to enlarge the communal delegations",
            "to imprision national leaders charging the traitors to the nation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The massacre of the crowd at Jallianwala Bagh at Amritsar took place on",
        "answer": "April 13, 1919",
        "choices": [
            "April 13, 1919",
            "May 5, 1918",
            "April 1, 1919",
            "July 29, 1919"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Why did people gather to demonstrate at Jallianwala Bagh?",
        "answer": "to protest against the arrest of Kitchlu and Satyapal",
        "choices": [
            "to protest against the arrest of Kitchlu and Satyapal",
            "To protest against the arrest of Gandhi and Lala Lajpat Rai",
            "to protest against the abritarily of inhuman acts of the Punjab Government",
            "to protest against General Dyer"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Rabindranath Tagore gave up his Knighthood because of ",
        "answer": "Jallianwala Bagh Massacre",
        "choices": [
            "Jallianwala Bagh Massacre",
            "Brutual supression of Civil Disobedience Movement",
            "Execution of Bhagat Singh",
            "Chauri Chaura Incident"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who from the following killed Micheal O Dwyer responsible for Jallianwala Bagh Massacre?",
        "answer": "Udham Singh",
        "choices": [
            "Udham Singh",
            "Prithvi Singh Azad",
            "Sardar Kishan Singh",
            "Sohan Singh Josh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Micheal O Dwyer was shot dead on 13th March 1940 in London by",
        "answer": "Udham Singh",
        "choices": [
            "Udham Singh",
            "Madan Lal Dhingra",
            "Veer Damodar Savarkar",
            "M P T Acharya"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the Prime Minister of England when Montague-Chlemsford Act was passed in 1919?",
        "answer": "David Llyod George",
        "choices": [
            "David Llyod George",
            "George Hamilton",
            "Samuel Hoare",
            "Salisbury"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Muddiman Committee was appointed to report on the working of the ",
        "answer": "Dyarchy",
        "choices": [
            "Dyarchy",
            "Communal Representation",
            "Fedralism",
            "Rowlatt Act"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which event served as a catalyst for the Khilafat Movement?",
        "answer": "The Treaty of Vesailles",
        "choices": [
            "The Treaty of Vesailles",
            "The Partition of Bengal",
            "The Jallianwala Bagh Massacre",
            "Arrival of Mahatma Gandhi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Why did Mahatma Gandhi support the Khilfat Movement?",
        "answer": "Gandhiji wanted to win the support of the Indian Muslims against the British",
        "choices": [
            "Gandhiji wanted to win the support of the Indian Muslims against the British",
            "The Khalifa had given shelter to Indian revolutionaries",
            "The Khalifa supported Indian struggle for freedom",
            "The Khalifa was a friend of Gandhiji"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who viewed the Khilafat Movement as an opportunity for integrating Hindus and Muslims which will not appear again within coming hundred years?",
        "answer": "Ali Brothers",
        "choices": [
            "Ali Brothers",
            "Abul Kalam Azad",
            "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "Khan Abdul Gaffar Khan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In which city was the conference of Khilafat Committee in 1920 held that requested Gandhiji to assume the leadership of Non-Cooperation Movement?",
        "answer": "Allahabad",
        "choices": [
            "Allahabad",
            "Lahore",
            "Lucknow",
            "Karachi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Moplah Rebellion in 1921 was an offshoot of",
        "answer": "Khilafat Movement",
        "choices": [
            "Khilafat Movement",
            "Mutiny of 1857",
            "Swadeshi Movement",
            "Non-Cooperation Movement"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Non-Cooperation Movement was started in",
        "answer": 1920,
        "choices": [
            1920,
            1919,
            1918,
            1921
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "A pleader of bihar who left his lucrative practice during non-cooperation movement was",
        "answer": "Rajendra Prasad",
        "choices": [
            "Rajendra Prasad",
            "Jai Prakash Narayan",
            "Sahjananad Saraswati",
            "Raj Kumar Shukla"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In which area was Rahul Sanrityayan active in the Non-Cooperation Movement of 1920?",
        "answer": "Chhapra",
        "choices": [
            "Chhapra",
            "Delhi",
            "Lucknow",
            "Patna"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who led cultivators in Bihar during the Non-Cooperation Movement?",
        "answer": "Swami Vidyanand",
        "choices": [
            "Swami Vidyanand",
            "Raj Kumar Shukla",
            "Shri Krishna Singh",
            "J B Sen"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "After which incident, Mahatma Gandhi halted the Non-Cooperation Movement and called it as his Himalayan Blunder?",
        "answer": "Chauri-Chaura",
        "choices": [
            "Chauri-Chaura",
            "Kakori Case",
            "Jallianwala Bagh Massacre",
            "Muzaffarpur Case"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who organized the  Swadesh Bandhav Samiti during the Indian Freedom Struggle?",
        "answer": "Ashwini Kumar Dutta",
        "choices": [
            "Ashwini Kumar Dutta",
            "Batukeshwar Dutta",
            "Surya Sen",
            "Surendranath Banerjee"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In which state is Chauri-Chaura where in February 1922 a police station was set on fire?",
        "answer": "Uttar Pradesh",
        "choices": [
            "Uttar Pradesh",
            "Madhya Pradesh",
            "Rajasthan",
            "Madhya Pradesh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "A Sanyasi who came to that district after a spell as an indentured labourer in Fiji, carrying a copy of Tulsidas Ramayana on his back from which he would recite verses to rural audience. The peasant leader refferred to here is",
        "answer": "Baba Ram Chandra",
        "choices": [
            "Baba Ram Chandra",
            "Jhinguri Singh",
            "Yadunandan Sharma",
            "Sahajananda Saraswati"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Swaraj Party was formed after the failure of the ",
        "answer": "Non-Cooperation Movement",
        "choices": [
            "Non-Cooperation Movement",
            "Quit India Movement",
            "Civil Disobedience Movement",
            "Swadeshi Movement"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who established the Swaraj Party in 1923",
        "answer": "Chittaranjan Das & Motilal Nehru",
        "choices": [
            "Chittaranjan Das & Motilal Nehru",
            "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "Vallabhbhai Patel",
            "Bhim Rao Ambedkar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who successfully led the Bardoli Satyagraha?",
        "answer": "Vallabhbhai Patel",
        "choices": [
            "Vallabhbhai Patel",
            "Motilal Nehru",
            "Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Jivatram Bhagwandas Kriplani"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which of the following movements was led and successful under the leadership of Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel?",
        "answer": "Satyagraha of Bardoli, Gujarat",
        "choices": [
            "Satyagraha of Bardoli, Gujarat",
            "Satyagraha in support of Khadi peasants, Gujarat",
            "Satyagraha of workers of cotton mills, Ahmedabad",
            "Champaran Satyagraha"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who established the Swaraj Dal in Bihar?",
        "answer": "Shri Krishna Singh",
        "choices": [
            "Shri Krishna Singh",
            "Ramlal Shah",
            "Bankim Chandra Chatterji",
            "Sachindra Nath Sanyal"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The famous slogan Swaraj should be for common people not only for classes was given by",
        "answer": "Chittaranjan Das",
        "choices": [
            "Chittaranjan Das",
            "Motilal Nehru",
            "Gopi Nath Saha",
            "Chakravarti Rajgopalachari"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Mahatma Gandhi presided over which session of the Inidan National Congress?",
        "answer": 1924,
        "choices": [
            1924,
            1922,
            1930,
            1928
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "When did Simon Commission visit India?",
        "answer": 1928,
        "choices": [
            1928,
            1929,
            1927,
            1931
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Nehru Report was drafted by a Committeee headed by",
        "answer": "Motilal Nehru",
        "choices": [
            "Motilal Nehru",
            "Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Vallabhbhai Patel",
            "Chittaranjan Das"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The proposal of Purna-Swaraj was passed in Lahore Congress in the year",
        "answer": 1929,
        "choices": [
            1929,
            1919,
            1942,
            1939
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who raised the flag of Independence at the Congress Session of 1929?",
        "answer": "Pandit Jawaharlal Nehru",
        "choices": [
            "Pandit Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Maulana Muhammad Ali",
            "Vallabhbhai Patel",
            "Subhas Chandra Bose"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which day was declared as Purna Swaraj Day by the Indian National Congress?",
        "answer": "26th January 1930",
        "choices": [
            "26th January 1930",
            "30th January 1948",
            "15th August 1947",
            "31st December 1950"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In which Sesssion Indian National Congress passed Complete Independence (Purna Swaraj) resolution?",
        "answer": "1929 Lahore",
        "choices": [
            "1929 Lahore",
            "1929 Nagpur",
            "1924 Belgaum",
            "1931 Karachi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Dandi March was undertaken in",
        "answer": 1930,
        "choices": [
            1930,
            1931,
            1932,
            1929
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who among the following participated in the Salt Satyagraha of Gandhi?",
        "answer": "All of these",
        "choices": [
            "All of these",
            "Sarojini Naidu",
            "Rajkumari Amrit Kaur",
            "Kamla Devi Chattopadhyaya"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The famous Dandi March led by Mahatma Gandhi during the Civil Disobedience Movement covered a distance of approximately",
        "answer": "241 miles (387 km)",
        "choices": [
            "241 miles (387 km)",
            "200 km",
            "400 km",
            "300 km"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In 1930, Mahatma Gandhi started Civil Disobedience Movement from",
        "answer": "Dandi",
        "choices": [
            "Dandi",
            "Sevagram",
            "Wardha",
            "Sabarmati"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "For how many days did Dandi March last?",
        "answer": "24 days",
        "choices": [
            "24 days",
            "10 days",
            "20 days",
            "30 days"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Agitation against Chaukidari Tax in Begusarai was a part of",
        "answer": "Civil Disobedience Movement",
        "choices": [
            "Civil Disobedience Movement",
            "Non-Cooperation Movement",
            "Quit India Movement",
            "Khilafat Movement"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who led the Salt Satyagraha in Bhagalpur",
        "answer": "Mahadev Lal Sarraf",
        "choices": [
            "Mahadev Lal Sarraf",
            "Shri Krishna Singh",
            "Kumar Mishra",
            "Satyanarayan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the founder of All India Harijan Sangh in 1932?",
        "answer": "Mahatma Gandhi",
        "choices": [
            "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "Dr Bhim Rao Ambedkar",
            "Jagjivan Ram",
            "Subhas Chandra Bose"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Prabhavati Devi was the freedom fighter from",
        "answer": "Patna",
        "choices": [
            "Patna",
            "Champaran",
            "Bhagalpur",
            "Shahabad"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Gandhi-Irwin pact was signed in",
        "answer": 1931,
        "choices": [
            1931,
            1935,
            1942,
            1919
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Second Round Table Conference in London was held in the backdrop of the",
        "answer": "Gandhi-Irwin Pact",
        "choices": [
            "Gandhi-Irwin Pact",
            "Emerson-Gandhi Pact",
            "Hailey-Gandhi Pact",
            "Gandhi-Simon Pact"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who played ann important role in the signing of Gandhi-Irwin Pact?",
        "answer": "Tej Bahadur Sapru",
        "choices": [
            "Tej Bahadur Sapru",
            "Motilal Nehru",
            "Madan Mohan Malviya",
            "Chintamani"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which of the following Indian leaders attended the First Round Table Conference in London?",
        "answer": "Maulana Mohammad Ali",
        "choices": [
            "Maulana Mohammad Ali",
            "Maulana Abul Kalam Azad",
            "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "Pandit Jawaharlal Nehru"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Indian National Congress did not take part in which of the following Round Table Conferences?",
        "answer": "First & Third",
        "choices": [
            "First & Third",
            "First",
            "Second",
            "Third"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Mahatma Gandhi returned to India in December, 1931 empty-handed from",
        "answer": "London",
        "choices": [
            "London",
            "Moscow",
            "Washington",
            "Tokyo"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "On which issue did the Second Round Table Conference fail?",
        "answer": "Communal Delegations",
        "choices": [
            "Communal Delegations",
            "Granting Dominion Status",
            "The date of transfer of ruling power",
            "Postponement of Civil Disobedience Movement"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which Round Table Conference held in 1932?",
        "answer": "Third",
        "choices": [
            "Third",
            "Second",
            "First",
            "Fourth"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who wrote the pamphlet Now or Never?",
        "answer": "Choudhary Rahmat Ali",
        "choices": [
            "Choudhary Rahmat Ali",
            "Muhammad Ali Jinnah",
            "Muhammad Iqbal",
            "Khafi Khan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "A separate electoral group was made by the communal Tribunal of Ramsay MacDonald first time in August, 1932",
        "answer": "for Untouchables",
        "choices": [
            "for Untouchables",
            "for Muslims",
            "for Indian Christians",
            "for Anglo-Indians"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "How many seats were given to depressed classes under Communal Award and Poona Pact?",
        "answer": "71 and 147 repectively",
        "choices": [
            "71 and 147 repectively",
            "74 and 79 respectively",
            "78 and 80 respectively",
            "78 and 69 respectively"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The purpose of Poona Pact was",
        "answer": "to provide representation of untouchables",
        "choices": [
            "to provide representation of untouchables",
            "Hindu-Muslim unity",
            "to priviledge the Kings",
            "Reconsideration of Dyarchy"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The first meeting of the Congress Socialist Party was held in",
        "answer": "Patna",
        "choices": [
            "Patna",
            "Nasik",
            "Delhi",
            "Lahore"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The first session of the Congress Socialist Party was held in the year",
        "answer": 1934,
        "choices": [
            1934,
            1921,
            1937,
            1939
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Congress Socialist Party was founded in 1934 by",
        "answer": "Jayaprakash Narayan & Acharya Narendra Dev",
        "choices": [
            "Jayaprakash Narayan & Acharya Narendra Dev",
            "Jawaharlal Nehru & Vinoba Bhave",
            "Jawaharlal Nehru & Jay Prakash Narayan",
            "Ashok Mehta & Dr Rajendra Prasad"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Jayprakash Narayan was associated with the which party",
        "answer": "Congress Socialist Pary",
        "choices": [
            "Congress Socialist Pary",
            "Communist Party",
            "Kisan Sabha",
            "Congress Party"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who formed the Bihar Socialist Party in 1931",
        "answer": "Phulan Prasad Verma",
        "choices": [
            "Phulan Prasad Verma",
            "Swami Yoginath",
            "Narhari Parikh",
            "Dadabhai Naoroji"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who started the Asiatic Society of Bengal in 1784?",
        "answer": "William Jones",
        "choices": [
            "William Jones",
            "Max Muller",
            "Charles William",
            "Charles Hardinge"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who is known as Loknayak",
        "answer": "Jayprakash Narayan",
        "choices": [
            "Jayprakash Narayan",
            "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "Subhash Chandra Bose",
            "Bal Gangadhar Tilak"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which title was given to Jayaprakash Narayan?",
        "answer": "Lok Nayak",
        "choices": [
            "Lok Nayak",
            "Praja Hitechlu",
            "Rashtra Nayak",
            "Lokmanya"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Jay Prakash diwas was celebrated in",
        "answer": "1946 April",
        "choices": [
            "1946 April",
            "1946 January",
            "1946 February",
            "1946 March"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Shri Narsingh Narayan was",
        "answer": "Socialist",
        "choices": [
            "Socialist",
            "Nationalist",
            "Internationalist",
            "Communist"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who became champion of socialism and wanted to overthrow British rule, Princely states, Landlordism and Capitalism in 1933?",
        "answer": "Jawaharlal Nehru",
        "choices": [
            "Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Rajendra Prasad",
            "Bhulabhai Dsai",
            "Sardar Patel"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The provincial Governments were consituted under the act of ",
        "answer": 1935,
        "choices": [
            1935,
            1932,
            1936,
            1947
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In which working Committee did the Congress adopt the policy of abolishing land ownership?",
        "answer": "Working Committee, 1937",
        "choices": [
            "Working Committee, 1937",
            "Working Committee, 1942",
            "Working Committee, 1945",
            "Working Committee, 1946"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was elected the President of Indian National Congress in 1938?",
        "answer": "Subhash Chandra Bose",
        "choices": [
            "Subhash Chandra Bose",
            "Abul Kalam Azad",
            "Pattabhi Sitaramaiya",
            "Jivatram Bhagwandas Kriplani"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The purpose of Butler Committee, 1927 was",
        "answer": "improvement of relationship between Indian Provinces and the Crown",
        "choices": [
            "improvement of relationship between Indian Provinces and the Crown",
            "Modernisation of Indian Army",
            "innovative modernisation of Indian Agriculture",
            "Implementation of censor over National Newspaper"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "All India State People's Conference was set up in",
        "answer": 1927,
        "choices": [
            1927,
            1924,
            1926,
            1929
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the British Prime Minister of Britain during the Second World War?",
        "answer": "Winston Churchill",
        "choices": [
            "Winston Churchill",
            "Clement Atlee",
            "Anthony Eden",
            "Herald Wilson"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who among the following led the movement for the separate State Pakistan?",
        "answer": "Muhammad Ali Jinnah",
        "choices": [
            "Muhammad Ali Jinnah",
            "Nawab Salimullah",
            "Aga Khan",
            "Liaquat Ali Khan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The resolution demanding the formation of Pakistan was passed by Muslim league in the year of",
        "answer": 1940,
        "choices": [
            1940,
            1939,
            1941,
            1942
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who started the Individual Satyagraha?",
        "answer": "Vinoba Bhave",
        "choices": [
            "Vinoba Bhave",
            "Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Sardar Patel",
            "Shauat Ali"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In 1940, Vinoba Bhave started individual Satyagraha from",
        "answer": "Pavnar, Maharashtra",
        "choices": [
            "Pavnar, Maharashtra",
            "Punnapra-Vayalar, Kerala",
            "Nadiad in Kheda district, Gujarat",
            "Patna, Bihar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the first Satyagrahi of the Individual Satyagraha Movement?",
        "answer": "Vinoba Bhave",
        "choices": [
            "Vinoba Bhave",
            "Chakravarti Rajgopalachari",
            "Subhash Chandra Bose",
            "Sarojini Naidu"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the second Satyagrahi of the Individual Satyagraha Movement?",
        "answer": "Jawaharlal Nehru",
        "choices": [
            "Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Vinoba Bhave",
            "Brahma Dutta",
            "Chakravarti Rajgopalachari"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the third Satyagrahi of the Individual Satyagraha Movement?",
        "answer": "Brahma Dutta",
        "choices": [
            "Brahma Dutta",
            "Vinoba Bhave",
            "Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Chakravarti Rajgopalachari"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who decided to oppose the war efforts peacefully by initiating a policy of Individual Civil Disobedience in 1941?",
        "answer": "Mahatma Gandhi",
        "choices": [
            "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "Tej Bahadur Sapru",
            "Maulana Abul Kalam Azad",
            "Jawaharlal Nehru"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The word Sarvodaya was primarily used by",
        "answer": "Mahatma Gandhi",
        "choices": [
            "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "Pandit Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Vinoba Bhave",
            "Jay Prakash Narayan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who viewed the Cripps proposal as a Post-dated cheque upon a crashing bank?",
        "answer": "Mahatma Gandhi",
        "choices": [
            "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "Pandit Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Jivatram Bhagwandas Kriplani",
            "Jay Prakash Narayan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In 1942, in which festival Jai Prakash Narayan escaped from Hazaribgh Jail?",
        "answer": "Deepawali",
        "choices": [
            "Deepawali",
            "Baisakhi",
            "Holi",
            "Dussehra"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "On 6th July, 1942 at the Working Committee of the Congress, Mahatma Gandhi discussed for the first time his Quit India Policy. The President of the Committee was",
        "answer": "Maulana Abul Kalam Azad",
        "choices": [
            "Maulana Abul Kalam Azad",
            "Chakravarti Rajgopalachari",
            "Pandit Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Annie Besant"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Quit India movement began on",
        "answer": "9th August 1942",
        "choices": [
            "9th August 1942",
            "15th August 1942",
            "10th August 1942",
            "16th August 1942"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The slogan Do or Die was related with",
        "answer": "Quit India Movement",
        "choices": [
            "Quit India Movement",
            "Dandi March",
            "Khilafat Satyagraha",
            "Non-Cooperation Movement"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "When did Baldev Sahai resigned from the post of Advocate General of Bihar?",
        "answer": 1942,
        "choices": [
            1942,
            1943,
            1913,
            1911
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Quit India Movement was led by",
        "answer": "Mahatma Gandhi",
        "choices": [
            "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "Bhim Rao Ambedkar",
            "Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Muhammad Ali Jinnah"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "On the outbreak of 1942, the people proclaimed the establishment of a National Government under Siaram Singh at",
        "answer": "Bhagalpur",
        "choices": [
            "Bhagalpur",
            "Patna",
            "Champaran",
            "Begusarai"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "All India Azad Dasta at Bakri Ka Tapu was organised during the Quit India Movement by",
        "answer": "Jay Prakash Narayan",
        "choices": [
            "Jay Prakash Narayan",
            "Ram Manohar Lohia",
            "Usha Mehta",
            "Chittu Pandey"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who organised the Azad Dasta?",
        "answer": "Jay Prakash Narayan",
        "choices": [
            "Jay Prakash Narayan",
            "Vinoba Bhave",
            "Jwala Prasad",
            "Chittu Pandey"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "During which movement Azad Dasta was active in Bihar?",
        "answer": "Quit India Movement",
        "choices": [
            "Quit India Movement",
            "Non-Cooperation Movement",
            "Champaran Movment",
            "Civil Disobedience Movement"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Prime Minister of England during the Quit India Movement?",
        "answer": "Winston Churchill",
        "choices": [
            "Winston Churchill",
            "Chamberlain",
            "Clement Atlee",
            "MacDonald"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who launched a secret radio during the Quit India Movement?",
        "answer": "Usha Mehta",
        "choices": [
            "Usha Mehta",
            "Subhadra Kumari Chauhan",
            "Sucheta Kriplani",
            "Annie Besant"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which area was affected widest with the communal riots due to Quit India Movement?",
        "answer": "Bihar & Uttar Pradesh",
        "choices": [
            "Bihar & Uttar Pradesh",
            "Bengal",
            "Gujarat",
            "Bihar & Bengal"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Dr Rajendra Prasad was arrested on 9th August 1942 and was sent to",
        "answer": "Bankipur Jail",
        "choices": [
            "Bankipur Jail",
            "Hazaribagh Jail",
            "Camp Jail",
            "Bhagalpur Jail"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "After passing the resolution of Quit India Movement Gandhiji was arrested in",
        "answer": "Aga Khan palace",
        "choices": [
            "Aga Khan palace",
            "Yarawada Jail",
            "Naini Jail",
            "Fort of Ahmednagar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "On 9th August 1942 the two arrested leaders of Hazaribagh were",
        "answer": "Shiv Kumar and Ramanand",
        "choices": [
            "Shiv Kumar and Ramanand",
            "Ramlal and Devilal",
            "Narayan Singh and Sukhlal Singh",
            "Ramnath and Devnath"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "With news of Gandhi and other Congress leaders arrest in 1942, a riot in Bihar took place, leading to a total breakdown in the rail services. The most affected area was",
        "answer": "Munger",
        "choices": [
            "Munger",
            "Gaya",
            "Patna",
            "Shahabad"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In which context did Jay Prakash Narayan get the recognition of national leader?",
        "answer": "Quit India Movement",
        "choices": [
            "Quit India Movement",
            "Establishment of Congress Socialist Party",
            "Bhoodan Movement",
            "Making the member of Congress Executive Committee"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who among the following escaped the Hazaribagh Jail during the Quit India Movement?",
        "answer": "Jay Prakash Narayan",
        "choices": [
            "Jay Prakash Narayan",
            "Jagjivan Ram",
            "Sachidanand Sinha",
            "Rafi Ahmed Kidwai"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Where was Shri Yogendra Shukla brought on the 7th December 1942",
        "answer": "Patna",
        "choices": [
            "Patna",
            "Ranchi",
            "Munger",
            "Bhagalpur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the wife of Mr Jagat Narayan Lal",
        "answer": "Rampyari Devi",
        "choices": [
            "Rampyari Devi",
            "Sundari Devi",
            "Bhagwati Devi",
            "Mangala Devi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who formed the Forward Bloc?",
        "answer": "Subhash Chandra Bose",
        "choices": [
            "Subhash Chandra Bose",
            "Rajendra Prasad",
            "Bhagat Singh",
            "Bhim Rao Ambedkar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In which country was the honorific - Netaji - added before the name of Subhash Chandra Bose?",
        "answer": "Germany",
        "choices": [
            "Germany",
            "India",
            "Italy",
            "Japan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who joined Subhas Chandra Bose to found All India Forward Bloc and actively associated with the INA movment?",
        "answer": "Sheel Bhadra Yajee",
        "choices": [
            "Sheel Bhadra Yajee",
            "Jay Prakash Narayan",
            "Baikunth Shukla",
            "Ram Narain Prasad"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The result of whose brains is INA and who founded it?",
        "answer": "Mohan Singh",
        "choices": [
            "Mohan Singh",
            "Subhas Chandra Bose",
            "Chandra Shekhar Azad",
            "Bhagat Singh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In which year was the Indian National Army founded?",
        "answer": 1942,
        "choices": [
            1942,
            1941,
            1943,
            1940
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Organisation of Azad Hind Fauz was declared on",
        "answer": "21st October 1943",
        "choices": [
            "21st October 1943",
            "26th January 1930",
            "8th August 1942",
            "18th February 1946"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Where was Azad Hind Fauz set up in 1943?",
        "answer": "Malaya",
        "choices": [
            "Malaya",
            "Japan",
            "Singapore",
            "Burma"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who among the following advocates had appeared for the INA trials at Delhi in 1945-46?",
        "answer": "Bhulabhai Desai",
        "choices": [
            "Bhulabhai Desai",
            "Dr Rajendra Prasad",
            "K M Munshi",
            "Sardar Patel"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "At the Congress Working Committee meeting at Allahabad (April-May 1947) who of the following members was able to secure a majority for his plan of a Guerilla War against the Japanese due to India's unequivocal stand against Nazism, Fascism and imperialism?",
        "answer": "Jawaharlal Nehru",
        "choices": [
            "Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Maulana Abul Kalam Azad",
            "Sarojini Naidu",
            "Subhas Chandra Bose"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who proceeded to organise the Provisional Government of Free India outside the country?",
        "answer": "Rash Behari Bose",
        "choices": [
            "Rash Behari Bose",
            "Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Raja Mahendra Pratap",
            "Darbhanga Raj"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "With which incident Subhas Chandra Bose compared to Napoleaon's March to Paris on his return from Elba?",
        "answer": "Mahatma Gandhi's Salt March",
        "choices": [
            "Mahatma Gandhi's Salt March",
            "Mahatma Gandhi's participation in Second Round Table Conference",
            "Mahatma Gandhi's Champaran Visit",
            "Mahatma Gandhi's Quit India Movement"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Cabinet Mission was sent to India for which of the following",
        "answer": "to work out a constitutional arrangement for the transfer of power",
        "choices": [
            "to work out a constitutional arrangement for the transfer of power",
            "to establish a national government",
            "to work out the details of Jinnah's demand for Pakistan",
            "All of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who among the following was not a member of the Cabinet Mission sent to India in 1946?",
        "answer": "Ramsay MacDonald",
        "choices": [
            "Ramsay MacDonald",
            "Standfford Cripps",
            "Albert Victor Alexander",
            "Pethick Lawrence"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Cabinet Mission was presided over by",
        "answer": "Pethick Lawrence",
        "choices": [
            "Pethick Lawrence",
            "Standfford Cripps",
            "Albert Victor Alexander",
            "Clement Attlee"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Cabinet Mission came to India in",
        "answer": "1946 March",
        "choices": [
            "1946 March",
            "1942 May",
            "1946 February",
            "1942 April"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which Congress President negotiated with both Cripps Mission and Wavell?",
        "answer": "Moulana Abul Kalam Azad",
        "choices": [
            "Moulana Abul Kalam Azad",
            "Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Jivatram Bhagwandas Kriplani",
            "Chakravarti Rajgopalachari"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was allotted the Portfolio of the Labour Department in the Interim Government's Cabinet of 1946",
        "answer": "Babu Jagjivan Ram",
        "choices": [
            "Babu Jagjivan Ram",
            "Rajendra Prasad",
            "Anugrah Narayan Sinha",
            "Syed Ali Zaheer"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who presided the first session of the Constituent Assemby formed in 1946",
        "answer": "Sachchidanand Sinha",
        "choices": [
            "Sachchidanand Sinha",
            "Rajendra Prasad",
            "Bhim Rao Ambedkar",
            "Jawaharlal Nehru"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Dr Rajendra Prasad was elected the Chairman of the Constituent Assembly in",
        "answer": "11th December 1946",
        "choices": [
            "11th December 1946",
            "11th November 1946",
            "9th November 1946",
            "9th December 1946"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "When was the first meeting of Constituent Assembly held",
        "answer": "9th December 1946",
        "choices": [
            "9th December 1946",
            "11th November 1946",
            "11th December 1946",
            "9th November 1946"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the Finance Minister in the Interim Government?",
        "answer": "Liaquat Ali Khan",
        "choices": [
            "Liaquat Ali Khan",
            "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
            "Muhammad Ali Jinnah",
            "Pandit Jawaharlal Nehru"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which portfolio did Rajendra Prasad hold in the interim government formed in 1946?",
        "answer": "Food & Agriculture",
        "choices": [
            "Food & Agriculture",
            "Finance",
            "Home",
            "Foreign Affairs"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the Congress President at the time of transfer of power in 1947 to India by the British?",
        "answer": "Jivatram Bhagwandas Kriplani",
        "choices": [
            "Jivatram Bhagwandas Kriplani",
            "Rajendra Prasad",
            "Maulana Abul Kalam Azad",
            "Jawaharlal Nehru"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the last Governor-General of Independent India",
        "answer": "Chakravarti Rajgopalachari",
        "choices": [
            "Chakravarti Rajgopalachari",
            "Rajendra Prasad",
            "Louis Mountbatten",
            "Charles Canning"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The first Indian to hold office as Governor-General of independent India was",
        "answer": "Chakravarti Rajgopalachari",
        "choices": [
            "Chakravarti Rajgopalachari",
            "Rajendra Prasad",
            "Surinder Nath",
            "Bhim Rao Ambedkar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "On February 20, 1947 Prime Minister Attlee announced the British Government's decision to withdraw from India latest by",
        "answer": "1948 June",
        "choices": [
            "1948 June",
            "1947 August",
            "1948 July",
            "1947 January"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who hailed free India's first Prime Minister Jawaharlal Nehru as an outstanding leader of courage and vision?",
        "answer": "Louis Mountbatten",
        "choices": [
            "Louis Mountbatten",
            "Moulana Abul Kalam Azad",
            "Sardar Patel",
            "Clement Attlee"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which incidents shocked British Prime Minister Clement Attlee, who had to declare that the edifice of the British imperialism had suffered a severe jolt?",
        "answer": "Campaign of the INA and Revolt of the Royal Indian Navy",
        "choices": [
            "Campaign of the INA and Revolt of the Royal Indian Navy",
            "Failure of Cabinet Mission",
            "Revolt of the Royal Indian Navy",
            "Rejection of the Cripps Mission"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Royal Indian Navy Mutiny, also known as the Bombay Mutiny took place in year",
        "answer": 1946,
        "choices": [
            1946,
            1945,
            1947,
            1948
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In which of the following Indian National Congress Sessions, the resolutions related to the Fundamental Rights were passed for the first time?",
        "answer": "Karachi 1931",
        "choices": [
            "Karachi 1931",
            "Surat 1907",
            "Gaya 1922",
            "Delhi 1947"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "When did the Indian Independence Bill get Royal Assent in England?",
        "answer": "18th July 1947",
        "choices": [
            "18th July 1947",
            "18th June 1947",
            "15th July 1947",
            "15th August 1947"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Under the provision of Regulating Act, a provincial Assembly for Bihar was set up in",
        "answer": 1774,
        "choices": [
            1774,
            1772,
            1776,
            1778
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "When did Bihar become a separate province in India?",
        "answer": 1912,
        "choices": [
            1912,
            1774,
            1905,
            1907
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which of the following Acts empowered Charles Cornwallis to overrule the decision of his Council?",
        "answer": "Amending Act of 1786",
        "choices": [
            "Amending Act of 1786",
            "Regulation Act of 1773",
            "Charter Act of 1853",
            "Charter Act of 1813"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which Act provisioned competitive exam system for Civil Services?",
        "answer": 1853,
        "choices": [
            1853,
            1833,
            1858,
            1882
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "To control the media in India, Acts were passed in",
        "answer": "1835, 1867, 1878, 1908",
        "choices": [
            "1835, 1867, 1878, 1908",
            "1854, 1864, 1872, 1910",
            "1854, 1872, 1908, 1910",
            "1867, 1908, 1910, 1919"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which of the following Acts introduced separate electorate system in India?",
        "answer": "Indian Councils Act, 1909",
        "choices": [
            "Indian Councils Act, 1909",
            "Regulating Act, 1773",
            "Charter Act of 1853",
            "Pitt's India Act, 1784"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Montagu-Chlemsford Report formed the basis of ",
        "answer": "Government of India Act, 1919",
        "choices": [
            "Government of India Act, 1919",
            "Government of India Act, 1947",
            "Government of India Act, 1935",
            "Indian Councils Act, 1909"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The post of the Indian High Commission was created by which Act?",
        "answer": "Government of India Act, 1919",
        "choices": [
            "Government of India Act, 1919",
            "Government of India Act, 1947",
            "Government of India Act, 1935",
            "Indian Councils Act, 1909"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who among the following became India's unofficial Ambassador to England?",
        "answer": "Dadabhai Naoroji",
        "choices": [
            "Dadabhai Naoroji",
            "Surendranath Banerjee",
            "Swami Vivekanand",
            "Subhas Chandra Bose"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Government of India Act, 1935 abolished",
        "answer": "Provincial Dyarchy",
        "choices": [
            "Provincial Dyarchy",
            "Provincial Autonomy",
            "Federal Structure of India",
            "Responsible Central Government"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who described the Government of India Act, 1935 as a Charter of Slavery?",
        "answer": "Jawaharlal Nehru",
        "choices": [
            "Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "Subhash Chandra Bose",
            "Maulana Hasrat Mohani"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "About which Act, Jawaharlal Nehru had said, We were provided with a car with all breaks and no engine?",
        "answer": "Government of India Act, 1935",
        "choices": [
            "Government of India Act, 1935",
            "Government of India Act, 1919",
            "Government of India Act, 1947",
            "Indian Councils Act, 1909"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which agreement failed to resolve the border issues between India and China, ultimately leading to the conflict?",
        "answer": "Panchsheel Agreement",
        "choices": [
            "Panchsheel Agreement",
            "Tashkent Agreement",
            "Shimla Agreement",
            "Tibet Agreement"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which Act is not landmark in the development of the Constitution during British Rule?",
        "answer": "Protection of Civil Rights, 1955",
        "choices": [
            "Protection of Civil Rights, 1955",
            "Regulating Act, 1773",
            "Charter Act of 1853",
            "Government of India Act, 1919"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "When did Sri Lanka become independent?",
        "answer": 1948,
        "choices": [
            1948,
            1945,
            1947,
            1950
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "During the freedom struggle, a parallel movement launched in the Indian States such as Kashmir, Hyderabad, Travancore etc was",
        "answer": "Praja Mandal Movement",
        "choices": [
            "Praja Mandal Movement",
            "Swaraj Movement",
            "State People's Movement",
            "Provincial Movement"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who started newspaper Motherland in September 1921 to disseminate the Hindu-Muslim unity and Gandhian ideology?",
        "answer": "Maulana Mazharul Haque",
        "choices": [
            "Maulana Mazharul Haque",
            "Anugrah Narayan Sinha",
            "Shambhu Sharan",
            "Shah Mohammad Zubair"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "On which date, Sukhdev, Bhagat Singh and Rajguru were hanged?",
        "answer": "23rd March 1931",
        "choices": [
            "23rd March 1931",
            "12th November 1930",
            "7th September 1931",
            "4th March 1931"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Where was Jhansi ki Rani Laxmibai died?",
        "answer": "Gwalior",
        "choices": [
            "Gwalior",
            "Kanpur",
            "Jhansi",
            "Lucknow"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Subhas Chandra Bose renamed Nicobar Island as",
        "answer": "Swaraj Island",
        "choices": [
            "Swaraj Island",
            "Shaheed Island",
            "Balidan Island",
            "Navodaya Island"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Subhas Chandra Bose renamed Andman Island as",
        "answer": "Shaheed Island",
        "choices": [
            "Shaheed Island",
            "Swaraj Island",
            "Balidan Island",
            "Navodaya Island"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Indian National Congress was founded on the basis of safety valve theory, to protect the British Government from threats. Which leader said that?",
        "answer": "Lala Lajpat Rai",
        "choices": [
            "Lala Lajpat Rai",
            "Chakravarti Rajgopalachari",
            "Bipin Chandra Pal",
            "Dadabhai Naoroji"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which of the following event happened first?",
        "answer": "Arrival of the Cripps Mission",
        "choices": [
            "Arrival of the Cripps Mission",
            "Quit India Movement",
            "Arrival of Wavell as the Governor General",
            "Arrival of Cabinet Mission"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Employee State Insuarance Act was passed in",
        "answer": 1948,
        "choices": [
            1948,
            1950,
            1951,
            1949
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Ramchandra Sharma belonged to which village?",
        "answer": "Amhara",
        "choices": [
            "Amhara",
            "Indrapur",
            "Gogri",
            "Pema"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who among the following Indian is known as Gurudev?",
        "answer": "Rabindra Nath Tagore",
        "choices": [
            "Rabindra Nath Tagore",
            "Chakravarti Rajgopalachari",
            "Lala Lajpat Rai",
            "Bhim Rao Ambedkar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who gave the slogan Jai Jawan Jai Kisan",
        "answer": "Lal Bahadur Sashtri",
        "choices": [
            "Lal Bahadur Sashtri",
            "Subhash Chandra Bose",
            "Devi Lal",
            "Morarji Desai"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "It will be our blunder if we leave people of Bihar and their Government unsafe before the violence and uncivilised attacks of league leaders. In year 1946 who spoke this?",
        "answer": "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
        "choices": [
            "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
            "Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Mahatama Gandhi",
            "Rajendra Prasad"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who raised the demand of Complete Independence for the first time in 1921",
        "answer": "Moulana Hasrat Mohani",
        "choices": [
            "Moulana Hasrat Mohani",
            "Maulana Muhammad Ali",
            "Pandit Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Mahatma Gandhi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Banaras Session of August, 1923 of the Hindu Mahasabha was presided over by",
        "answer": "Pandit Madan Mohan Malviya",
        "choices": [
            "Pandit Madan Mohan Malviya",
            "Swami Shraddhanda",
            "Rajendra Prasad",
            "Lala Lajpat Rai"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "In which year was Vinayak Damodar Savarkar elected the President of the Hindu Mahasabha?",
        "answer": 1937,
        "choices": [
            1937,
            1935,
            1919,
            1916
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The real name of the Frontier Gandhi is",
        "answer": "Abdul Gaffar Khan",
        "choices": [
            "Abdul Gaffar Khan",
            "Maulana Abul Kalam Azad",
            "Purshottam Das Tandon",
            "Netaji Subhash Chandra Bose"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Ambabai, a woman freedom fighter, belonged to which of the following States of India?",
        "answer": "Karnataka",
        "choices": [
            "Karnataka",
            "Kerala",
            "Andhra Pradesh",
            "Madhya Pradesh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Rajendra Prasad belonged to",
        "answer": "Bihar",
        "choices": [
            "Bihar",
            "Uttar Pradesh",
            "Madhya Pradesh",
            "Punjab"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Jagat Narayan Lal was sent to",
        "answer": "Hazaribagh Jail",
        "choices": [
            "Hazaribagh Jail",
            "Bankipur Jail",
            "Camp Jail",
            "Bhagalpur Jail"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "To establish global peace and cooperation among the people, which of the following concept introduced by the Jawaharlal Nehru?",
        "answer": "Non-Alignment",
        "choices": [
            "Non-Alignment",
            "Panchsheel",
            "Peaceful Coexistence",
            "Akhand Bharat"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Name the Deoband scholar who played a significant role in freedom movement.",
        "answer": "Abul Kalam Azad",
        "choices": [
            "Abul Kalam Azad",
            "Muhammad Ali Jinnah",
            "Badruddin Tyabji",
            "Chirag Ali"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who organised the Khudai Khidmatgar in 1929?",
        "answer": "Khan Abdul Gaffar Khan",
        "choices": [
            "Khan Abdul Gaffar Khan",
            "Ali Brothers",
            "Ansari Brothers",
            "Maulana Abul Kalam Azad"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "When was the Punjab Land Alienation Act passed?",
        "answer": 1900,
        "choices": [
            1900,
            1850,
            1895,
            1905
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Department of State was established under whose headship?",
        "answer": "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
        "choices": [
            "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
            "Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Mahatama Gandhi",
            "G B Pant"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The objective of Antodaya program is ",
        "answer": "to help the poorest of poor",
        "choices": [
            "to help the poorest of poor",
            "development of minorities",
            "advancement of Dalits",
            "complete eradication of poverty"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who is considered as the creator of Modern Bihar?",
        "answer": "Sachchidanand Sinha",
        "choices": [
            "Sachchidanand Sinha",
            "Kumar Kalika Prasad Sinha",
            "Acharya Narendra Dev",
            "Jai Prakash Narayan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Religious Organisation established by Mother Teresa is called",
        "answer": "Missionaries of Charity",
        "choices": [
            "Missionaries of Charity",
            "Sisters of Charity",
            "Organisation of Love",
            "Charity of all"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which organisation of India has the motto, Dharmo Rakshati Rakshitah?",
        "answer": "Research and Analysis Wing",
        "choices": [
            "Research and Analysis Wing",
            "Indian Army",
            "Indian Supreme Court",
            "Indian Navy"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Indian Nationalist leader who delivered lecture on Joseph Mazzini and the Young Italy movement was",
        "answer": "Surendranath Banerjee",
        "choices": [
            "Surendranath Banerjee",
            "Subhash Chandra Bose",
            "Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Mahatma Gandhi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Welby Commission 1895 was constituted on which of the following matters?",
        "answer": "Indian Expenditure",
        "choices": [
            "Indian Expenditure",
            "Education in India",
            "Land Revenue",
            "Indian Military"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Hitler's autobiography which outlined his political ideology and future plans for Germany, is titled",
        "answer": "Mein Kampf",
        "choices": [
            "Mein Kampf",
            "Das Kapital",
            "Communist Manifesto",
            "Tryst with Truth"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who wrote the book, India Divided?",
        "answer": "Rajendra Prasad",
        "choices": [
            "Rajendra Prasad",
            "Maulana Abul Kalam Azad",
            "Penderel Moon",
            "Ambra Prasad"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which one of the following was a journal brought out by Abul Kalam Azad?",
        "answer": "Al-Hilal",
        "choices": [
            "Al-Hilal",
            "Hunkar",
            "Zamindar",
            "The Comrade"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who started the journal Bahishkrit Bharat?",
        "answer": "Babasahed Ambedkar",
        "choices": [
            "Babasahed Ambedkar",
            "Jyotiba Phule",
            "Karsandas Mulji",
            "Bal Gangadhar Tilak"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which one of the following books was written by Tilak?",
        "answer": "Gita Rahasya",
        "choices": [
            "Gita Rahasya",
            "India in Transition",
            "Gokhale-My Political Guru",
            "Discovery of India"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the author of the book, Mahatma Gandhi and Bihar: Some Reminiscences?",
        "answer": "Rajendra Prasad",
        "choices": [
            "Rajendra Prasad",
            "Syed Ali Zaheer",
            "Jivatram Bhagwandas Kriplani",
            "Raj Kumar Shukla"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "What was the name of the first book of Raja Ram Mohan Roy published in 1815?",
        "answer": "Vedanta Grantha",
        "choices": [
            "Vedanta Grantha",
            "Tuhfat-ul-Muwahhidin",
            "Bharathi Vilasa",
            "Shakuntalam"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the author of Indian Unrest?",
        "answer": "Valentine Chirol",
        "choices": [
            "Valentine Chirol",
            "Dadabhai Naoroji",
            "Annie Besant",
            "Lala Lajpat Rai"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who has written the book Unhappy India?",
        "answer": "Lala Lajpat Rai",
        "choices": [
            "Lala Lajpat Rai",
            "Bal Gangadhar Tilak",
            "Annie Besant",
            "Allan Octavian Hume"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who wrote the book, Poverty and un-British Rule in India?",
        "answer": "Dadabhai Naoroji",
        "choices": [
            "Dadabhai Naoroji",
            "R C Dutta",
            "Bipin Chandra Pal",
            "Lala Lajpat Rai"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who had translated the Bengali play, Nil Darpan into English?",
        "answer": "Micheal Madhusudan Dutt",
        "choices": [
            "Micheal Madhusudan Dutt",
            "Dinabandhu Mitra",
            "James Long",
            "Antonio Gramsci"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who wrote the book, India for Indians?",
        "answer": "Chittaranjan Das",
        "choices": [
            "Chittaranjan Das",
            "M G Ranade",
            "Vinayak Damodar Savarkar",
            "Surendranath Banerjee"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The novel Durgesha Nandini is written by",
        "answer": "Bankim Chandra Chatterjee",
        "choices": [
            "Bankim Chandra Chatterjee",
            "Rabindranath Tagore",
            "Taraknath Gangopadhayaya",
            "Swarna Kumari"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The temple of Deogarh near Jhansi and the sculptures in the temples at Garhwa near Allahabad are the important remains of the",
        "answer": "Gupta Art",
        "choices": [
            "Gupta Art",
            "Maurya Art",
            "Rashtrakuta Art",
            "Mughal Art"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Pietra Dura is related to which of the following?",
        "answer": "Decorating the walls with floral designs made of semi-precious stones",
        "choices": [
            "Decorating the walls with floral designs made of semi-precious stones",
            "building sloping walls in Minars",
            "Use of arch in constuction",
            "use of marble in buildings"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Brihadisvara Temple in Thanjavur was constructed by which King?",
        "answer": "Rajaraja I",
        "choices": [
            "Rajaraja I",
            "Rajendra I",
            "Rajendra II",
            "Kulottunga I"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The mighty gateways found at the temples of South India are called",
        "answer": "Gopurams",
        "choices": [
            "Gopurams",
            "Shikhars",
            "Devalayas",
            "Mandaps"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Name the Mughal emperor who was proclaimed the Shahenshah-e-Hindustan by the rebels of 1857",
        "answer": "Bhadur Shah Zafar",
        "choices": [
            "Bhadur Shah Zafar",
            "Bahadur Shah I",
            "Ahmad Shah Bahadur",
            "Akbar Shah II"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Name the political agent in Delhi who was killed by mutinying sepoys in the revolt of 1857",
        "answer": "Simon Fraser",
        "choices": [
            "Simon Fraser",
            "William Fraser",
            "John Nicholson",
            "Major Charlie Burton"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which region of India was least affected by the revolt of 1857?",
        "answer": "South India",
        "choices": [
            "South India",
            "North India",
            "Western India",
            "Central India"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Mangal Pandey belonged to which regiment before his execution?",
        "answer": "34th Native Infantry",
        "choices": [
            "34th Native Infantry",
            "24th Native Infantry",
            "19th Native Infantry",
            "7th Native Infantry"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which of Bankim Chandra Chattopadhyay's novels is set against the backdrop of the Sanyasi Rebellion and the Great Bengal Famine of 1770?",
        "answer": "Anandamath",
        "choices": [
            "Anandamath",
            "Durgeshnandini",
            "Krishnakanter Will",
            "Kapalkundala"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Sanyasi Rebellion took place during which period?",
        "answer": "1763-1800",
        "choices": [
            "1763-1800",
            "1757-1764",
            "1800-1820",
            "1857-1858"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Sanyasi Rebellion primarily broke out in which region of India?",
        "answer": "Bengal and Bihar",
        "choices": [
            "Bengal and Bihar",
            "Awadh",
            "Deccan",
            "Punjab"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who among the following was associated with the Sanyasi Rebellion as a woman leader?",
        "answer": "Devi Chaudhurani",
        "choices": [
            "Devi Chaudhurani",
            "Rani Durgavati",
            "Rani Lakshmibai",
            "Rani Chennamma"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Chuar Uprising primarily took place in which region of India?",
        "answer": "Jungle Mahal region of Bengal",
        "choices": [
            "Jungle Mahal region of Bengal",
            "Chota Nagpur Plateau",
            "Malabar Coast",
            "North-East India"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Chuar Uprising began in which year?",
        "answer": 1766,
        "choices": [
            1766,
            1770,
            1793,
            1757
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who among the following women leaders was associated with the Chuar Uprising?",
        "answer": "Rani Shiromani of Karnagarh",
        "choices": [
            "Rani Shiromani of Karnagarh",
            "Devi Chaudhurani",
            "Rani Lakshmibai",
            "Rani Chennamma"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Bhil Uprising mainly took place in which part of India?",
        "answer": "Satpura and Western Ghats region",
        "choices": [
            "Satpura and Western Ghats region",
            "Chota Nagpur Plateau",
            "Aravalli Ranges",
            "Jungle Mahal region of Bengal"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Santhal Hool began from which village?",
        "answer": "Bhognadih",
        "choices": [
            "Bhognadih",
            "Raipur",
            "Karnagarh",
            "Dhadka"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who were the women leaders associated with the Santhal Hool?",
        "answer": "Phulo and Jhano Murmu",
        "choices": [
            "Phulo and Jhano Murmu",
            "Rani Shiromani and Devi Chaudhurani",
            "Lakshmibai and Rani Chennamma",
            "None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The region known in colonial records as Damin-i-Koh, created by the British for the settlement of the Santhals, is geographically part of which of the following hills?",
        "answer": "Rajmahal Hills",
        "choices": [
            "Rajmahal Hills",
            "Aravalli Range",
            "Garo Hills",
            "Nilgiri Hills"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which Act was passed as a result of the Munda Rebellion?",
        "answer": "Chotanagpur Tenancy Act 1908",
        "choices": [
            "Chotanagpur Tenancy Act 1908",
            "Bengal Tenancy Act 1885",
            "Santhal Pargana Act 1856",
            "Scheduled Tribes Act 1950"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Indigo Revolt took place in",
        "answer": "1859-60",
        "choices": [
            "1859-60",
            "1855-56",
            "1857-58",
            "1862-63"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Indigo Revolt started from which village",
        "answer": "Govindpur, Nadia",
        "choices": [
            "Govindpur, Nadia",
            "Champaran",
            "Pabna",
            "Birbhum"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who were the main leaders of the Indigo Revolt?",
        "answer": "Digambar Biswas and Bishnu Biswas",
        "choices": [
            "Digambar Biswas and Bishnu Biswas",
            "Sidhu and Kanhu Murmu",
            "Birsa Munda and Gaya Munda",
            "Tilka Manjhi and Bhavani Pathak"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which play exposed the exploitation of indigo planters?",
        "answer": "Neel Darpan",
        "choices": [
            "Neel Darpan",
            "Anandamath",
            "Nilgiri Hills",
            "Bharat Durdasha"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Indigo Commission was appointed in",
        "answer": 1860,
        "choices": [
            1860,
            1857,
            1862,
            1875
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Indigo Revolt was supported by which Bengali newspaper?",
        "answer": "Hindoo Patriot",
        "choices": [
            "Hindoo Patriot",
            "The Statesman",
            "Amrit Bazar Patrika",
            "Bangadarshan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Who was the editor of Hindoo Patriot?",
        "answer": "Harish Chandra Mukherjee",
        "choices": [
            "Harish Chandra Mukherjee",
            "Shishir Kumar Ghose",
            "S N Banerjee",
            "Girish Chandra Ghose"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Bengal Tenancy Act was enacted during the viceroyalty of",
        "answer": "George Frederick - Ripon",
        "choices": [
            "George Frederick - Ripon",
            "Charles Canning",
            "Robert Bulwer - Lytton",
            "George Curzon"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which of the following movements influenced the Bengal Tenancy Act?",
        "answer": "Pabna Agrarian Revolt",
        "choices": [
            "Pabna Agrarian Revolt",
            "Santhal Rebellion",
            "Indigo Revolt",
            "Munda Ulgulan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "According to the Bengal Tenancy Act, a cultivator obtained occupancy right after cultivating land continuously for",
        "answer": "12 years",
        "choices": [
            "12 years",
            "15 years",
            "20 years",
            "10 years"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Pabna Agrarian Revolt took place during the viceroyalty of",
        "answer": "Northbrook",
        "choices": [
            "Northbrook",
            "Canning",
            "Lytton",
            "Ripon"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Pabna Revolt was mainly against",
        "answer": "Zamindars",
        "choices": [
            "Zamindars",
            "European Planters",
            "Moneylenders",
            "Colonial Government"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "Which political organisation is associated with the Pabna Revolt?",
        "answer": "Indian Association",
        "choices": [
            "Indian Association",
            "Indian National Congress",
            "Bengal Presidency Association",
            "British Indian Association"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Pabna Revolt led to passage of which Act?",
        "answer": "Bengal Tenancy Act, 1885",
        "choices": [
            "Bengal Tenancy Act, 1885",
            "Permanent Settlement Act",
            "Rent Act, 1859",
            "Ryotwari Settlement Act"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "HistoryModern",
        "question": "The Deccan Riots of 1875 began in which region?",
        "answer": "Poona (Pune) and Ahmednagar (Ahilyanagar)",
        "choices": [
            "Poona (Pune) and Ahmednagar (Ahilyanagar)",
            "Bengal Presidency",
            "Awadh Region",
            "Madras Presidency"
        ]
    }
]